Heat. Heat.
Hello. Good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Ask
Abij show. This is episode 338 and we
are discussing the Gulf War, the Iran
war, the USIsrael versus Iran war.
What's happening as always it's an it's
a developing situation. Uh so we're
going to discuss that. I'm going to take
as many questions as possible about that
topic mainly. But before we do that
let's see who all is there on the live
stream with us. I can see Axit Sharma
Shri Rama Chandra Naha. Hello Utkar
Shukla Kamill Bira Geopolitical Dubai
from Indoor Karn Singh Pund
cool short 5763 Swami Nirvana Shashags
Salve
uh Freakster someone 123 N7W Sky Glider
SK Sky Glider S Namaste um Aush Gupta
Mory Jham Shri Raachandra once again
tanesh Pandi Omar Date Hello Raguir
Soleni Ashish Chri
Pramanic Namaskar Sumit Garval
Soldier Boy Panduranga Rula Saksham
Jaserya cool short Aush Singh Aush Singh
Praam Danesh Pande uh Kapalin Pyanchi
Sud Om just sing uh cool short 5760 once
again Um Marshall Si Saksham Jasroia
Astas Aasaro
good to see you good to see you Mahita
Bushetti hello Satyam Chowri Abhishek
Shukla live Putin is taking charge says
Swami is here from Jaipur Bali today uh
Han Badger of Kolinga hello Arindam roy
hello tanesh Pand joti panda namaskar
ashai hello Marshall si frost mistra
mitra is here from Moscow pranam Hello,
Abininov Kapil is here from Himachal.
Praav Pam SKR is here from Jerusalem.
Okay, I see what you did there. Ram Ram
uh Chetanya Manuja Stanley Rohit Gomez.
Um Jayant S121, Anud Sahu, uh Random
Skull, hello, good to see you. Mia,
Soldier Boy,
who else do we have? Shrii is here. Anya
is here. Ravalite is here. Viri WHMA I
Sager Dimani just a word away someone
vs. Hello. Good to see you. Toxic Kratos
hello. Uh Sundaram is here from Canada.
Akit Akshit Sharma is also here and yeah
everyone else Manhattan Manhattan is
also here. Nirvana Shanks and everyone
else. Okay. So let us discuss the
situation the evolving situation in West
Asia. The war is escalating. Escalating.
Let's first take a look at some of the
things that are happening right now
essentially in real time or in the past
in the past few hours. Give me a second.
Where's the thing?
Okay, let's put this on the screen.
Let's see what's happening right now.
So, this is u it's in Arabic, but let's
translate this.
Uh this is the AD media office, the
official account of the Abu Dhabi media
office. Okay. And it says that the
competent authorities in the emirate of
Abu Dhabi are dealing with a fire that
broke out in one of the facilities
within the Rice industrial complex
resulting from a drone attack with no
injuries recorded so far. The competent
authorities urged the public to obtain
official sources only and so on and so
forth. Okay. So the the Ruice Industrial
Complex in Abu Dhabi, it is the largest
oil refinery in West Asia
and it's one of the largest single sight
refineries in the entire world. It has
been hit by a drone strike. Okay, it's a
drone strike.
Uh let's search for Rice, shall we?
Let's search for Rice.
What's going on in Ruice?
So, this is an evolving situation. It's
developing news. Uh, what does this say?
The UA's largest refinery has been
stuck. This was struck. This was no
random industrial site. This is Adnox
Rice refinery. Adno is Abu Dhabi
National Oil Corporation. One of the
major oil producers in the world. Adno.
Uh so the ROI processes up to 837,000
barrels of crude oil every single day.
It's located on the Arabian Gulf Coast
about 245 km west of Abu Dhabi. It's the
heart of UA's oil exports,
petrochemicals and strategic reserves
uh etc etc etc. And they are saying US,
Israel or Iran just hit the UAE where it
hurts most. It's oil lifeline. Global
oil markets already reacting. This
changes everything. Okay. So I Yeah,
this looks like um Yeah, I don't know
who this is. And they said that US,
Israel or Iran just just hit the UAE.
Interesting way of putting it. Yeah. So
obviously the blame is going to go on
Iran and most likely it makes sense that
it must have been Iran but you never
know. You never know. So this is a major
escalation and this happened just uh 2
three hours ago. I mean the news came
out 2 three hours ago. What else is
happening? This is uh by Ali Larijani.
Um
and what's it say? This is a post by
Donald Trump. Trump says if Iran does
anything that stops the flow of oil
within the straight of Hormuz, they will
be hit by the United States of America
20 times harder in capitals than they
have been hit thus far. Additionally, we
will take out easily destroyable targets
that will make it virtually impossible
for Iran to ever be built back as a
nation. again death, fire and fury will
rain upon them but I hope and pray that
it does not happen. This is a gift from
the US United States of America to China
and all those nations that heavily use
the hormones straight. Hopefully it's a
gesture that will be greatly
appreciated. Thank you etc etc. And what
does Ali Lariji Jani say? The Ashura
living nation of Iran does not fear your
paper threats. Even those greater than
you could not eliminate the Iranian
nation. Watch out for yourself lest you
be eliminated. That's what Ali Lariji
Jani says. Um,
Ali Lariji Jani. Uh, who is Ali Ali Lari
Jani? Let's find out.
Ali Lari Jani. He is an Iranian
politician, former military officer in
the IRGC.
He's a senior politician in Iran. Uh,
what else do we have? Yeah, we have
Trump.
Trump said, "Why don't we just Trump
said that?" I said, "Why don't we just
capture that ship? We could use it. Why
did we sink it?" And the commander of
the of the American submarine said it's
more fun to sink them. They like sinking
sinking them better. So from what Trump
is saying, this is in reference to the
ship, the Iranian ship that was
torpedoed uh right outside of India's
territorial uh waters in it was
torpedoed in international waters but in
India's uh zone of interest south of Sri
Lanka.
So from what Trump is saying, it looks
like uh the captain of the submarine had
a choice of either capturing or sinking
the ship. He had a choice of either
capturing or sinking the ship. And he
said that it's more fun to sink them. So
he torpedoed the ship and he allowed the
sailors
to drown. This sounds very suspiciously
like a war crime.
But I suspect if the US does it, it's
perfectly fine. Yeah. Uh yeah. So this
is kind of what's happening right now.
Uh UA's oil major oil refinery has been
has been struck. Okay. Is this real
image? Is it is it fake? You never know.
these days,
right? Um, what does it say?
Okay. Okay. Okay. Long, long, long
story.
Long story. Anyhow, this is kind of
what's happening in the West Asia region
right now. Um,
so it's escalating. The situation is
escalating. Trump is making major
threats. Uh, the the straight of
hormones is still closed. uh Chinese
ships are being allowed to pass by Iran
but no other ships dare to pass right
now. So that's causing an oil price rise
across the world which is a major
problem for everybody including us in
India. There are nations that are
already um you know beginning to ration
whether it's LG whether it's petroleum
whether it's fuel. Yeah, that process is
beginning. Uh, and this is going to if
if it if the straight remains closed,
it's going to be a major problem for
India, China, uh, Japan and other
nations as well east of uh, the straight
of Hormos and other nations around the
world as well because oil prices will
rise globally. In the US, gas prices,
gasoline prices have already risen by
more than a dollar it looks like. And
this is going to be a problem for Trump
because it's going to um displease his
core voter base, his vote bank. It's
going to be problematic for him. Um
yeah, so that's the situation. Now my
analysis about what's happening, I put
it out on Twitter, but let me read it
out for you all over here. Let's do
that. Okay. Okay. Let's make it larger.
So this is my this is a very brief
analysis that I put on Twitter. My
analysis is actually much deeper but on
Twitter you put it you keep it short. So
operation epic fury tactically
successful strategically selfdefeating.
So war is supposed to be the
continuation of politics by other means.
War is supposed to be the continuation
of politics by other means. But the
current US campaign versus Iran has
inverted this relationship. Military
action is being pursued in the absence
of a coherent political objective with
this political objective somehow
expected to emerge expected to somehow
emerge from the military action.
Okay. So politics is not war by other
means. War is supposed to be politics by
other means. So there's military action
being taken by the Americans and they
are expecting that somehow the political
objective will emerge out of our
warfare.
They what it means translated into
regular language. It means they don't
know what they want to achieve.
Their goalposts have been changing from
day one to day two to all the way now.
Initially it was regime change.
Initially Trump was saying that you know
what people of Iran go ahead and we
we're going to destroy this regime and
you you can take over. So Trump expected
that if he kills Kabani then the regime
is over and the people of Iran can take
over. But that's not what happened. It
was a miscalculation. Then he's moved
this gold post and he's saying that now
it's something else denuclearization,
demissilization and so on so forth. So
not regime change anymore. Then what are
you doing?
So they are not sure what they want to
achieve. Their their goalposts keep
changing. So
military action is being pursued in the
absence of a coherent political
objective and they expect that this
political objective will will emerge
somehow from the military action. So
this is the worst kind of category error
because it cannot be corrected by better
targeting or more aircraft sorties or
more missile strikes. It can't be
corrected by any of that. Military
action can't correct this category
error. Okay. Now thus far the US
campaign to date has achieved
significant tactical success and the
credit for this goes to the American
military. They have destroyed a lot of
Iranian military nuclear infrastructure.
Apparently they have obviously killed
how many assassinated him and all the
top leadership of Iran. They have
suppressed a lot of Iran's air defenses.
But this has produced strategic
stalemate. Iran is absorbing the strikes
of the Americans and the Israelis and at
the same time it is maintaining its
offensive capability, its offensive
capacity. It is maintaining the closure
of the spread of Hermuz. And it's
maintaining the activity of its allies,
its proxies.
whether it's Isbaha whether it is the
Houthis whether it is Iraq militias etc
right so this is ongoing this is a
stalemate and this why has this
stalemate occurred this stalemate has
occurred because despite being
tactically successful the American
campaign is operationally incoherent and
strategically selfdee defeating and the
the credit for this goes to Donald Trump
okay so how is it incoherent how is it
strategically self-defeating despite
being tactically successful. First of
all, the tactical destruction of Iranian
military or nuclear facilities does not
translate into the operational control
of Iran's missile forces. Those are
still being 100% controlled by Iran, by
the IRGC and the Iranian military.
That's number one. Number two, the
operational su suppression by America of
Iran's air defenses does not produce the
strategic collapse of the IRGC, the
Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps. It's
not going to produce that. Okay. Number
three, the strategic decapitation of
Kame does not produce a compliant
successor government in the absence of
physical occupation. To produce a
compliant successor government, you have
to physically occupy the territory. and
the Americans are unwilling to
physically occupy the territory or even
attempt that. Right? So, it's not
produced a compliant appable successor
government. The IRGC's redundant command
structure, distributed leadership and
ideological cohesion mean that the loss
of any one person, any individual
including the supreme leader does not
collapse the system. It doesn't collapse
the system. One person dies doesn't
matter. Right? Iran has been
successfully able to appoint a new
supreme leader without any operational
interruption of its war fighting of its
war efforts. Nothing was interrupted.
Right. Next number four. Carpet bombing.
The Americans are carpet bombing the
Iranian population. Carpet bombing the
Iranian populace and obliterating their
infrastructure and their oil reserves
does not induce them to overthrow the
government. It does not indeting
the people and destroying their
infrastructure. It does not induce those
people who you are bombing to overthrow
the government. It produces the opposite
effect. It reinforces nationalist
cohesion. The people rally around the
flag. Even those who are opposing the
government of Iran, even they will now
rally around the flag. Right? Then the
Americans are thinking the are thinking
of maybe uh using mercenaries, using
proxies like the Kuresh mercenaries,
maybe ISIS terrorists, maybe somebody
else. Okay. So if the Americans go for
forward with this plan proxy invasion of
Iran that will take years to make any
inroads and it is most likely almost
100% almost 100% guaranteed to fail as
Saddam Hussein discovered okay it's not
easy to invade Iran and Saddam had a
full professional military who are ISIS
and who are the Kuresh mercenaries
they're nothing compared to Saddam right
next Trump has a huge
acute
political vulnerability. It's a very
near-term political vulnerability.
He has imposed a 4-week political window
for wrapping up this operation. Okay,
this military operation by the United
States, it's it's costing almost a
billion dollars a day. Last I checked,
it was $890, $891 million per day. It's
burning through cash. Okay, so huge
costs every day. The oil prices are
rising. They're shooting up and there is
congressional opposition to what Trump
is doing. Okay. So, all of this is going
to converge into one hard culminating
point for Trump. He doesn't have time.
Sentiment is growing against him in the
United States whether it's in the
opposition or within whether it's among
his own supporters. Okay? And even the
nuclear option is unlikely to defeat the
Iranian mosaic warfare strategy, the
decentralized warfare strategy.
And we know that a religiously motivated
Shia Iran that embraces martyrdom will
be happy to fight on. a nuclear
explosion will or nuclear attacks won't
make a difference to their uh to their
uh resolve to fight out and their desire
to die in in in service of the nation.
Right? So the because of all these
factors
the American campaign it's it's
approaching its culminating point.
Okay. The superiority of the attacker
the Americans and Israel is over the
defender which is Iranians is close to
being consumed.
H continued offensive action thereafter
will produce diminishing returns rather
than increasing returns for the
attacker.
So the US
is in a situation where it it is
unwilling to put boots on the ground. No
major military campaign has ever been
won from altitude.
No major military campaign has been won
from altitude from up in the sky. You
have to put boots on the ground
otherwise you don't achieve your
political objectives. It's as simple as
that. You can win minor campaigns from
altitude but you can't win a major
campaign like this from altitude. That's
what history tells you. Right? So this
so the United States cannot win a
protracted
campaign without wi with the instruments
and constraints it has deployed. It has
two choices. Either it terminates the
campaign on achievable limited terms or
the alternative is it escalates to
occupation which is boots on the ground
but it's unfeasible due to domestic
political sentiment or the US must wait
for its own culminating point which is
essentially a failure of to achieve any
any any significant objectives right uh
see there is massive domestic political
sentiment against a US ground invasion
of Iran
There are two populations here. There's
the Iranians who are fighting for the
survival of Iran and there's the
American soldiers who are fighting for
the capture of another nation's oil
resources. Who will be more motivated?
Who will be willing to die for the
cause? Obviously, those who are fighting
for their homeland and its survival. The
ones who are who are out for plunder,
they will not be willing to die for
plunder. So that's the dichotomy here.
Okay. So the situation is that Iran only
needs to do one thing. It needs not to
lose. It needs to not lose. All Iran has
to do is to sustain the hormones, the
straight of hormones blockade. Each day
of disrupted tanker traffic generates
more pressure on Trump's sore point on
his Achilles heel, domestic political
will, than any number of missile
strikes. And the question is, can Iran
sustain this blockade long enough? And
even if let's say Iran for some reason
is unable to sustain the blockade still
it is not defeated and still the costs
keep rising for Trump
in the region in the Gulf region it
looks like a significant number of
American military uh bases have been
struck by Iran whether they have been
significantly degraded or entirely
destroyed doesn't it's not out in the
open it's not out in the public domain
when a war is going on you don't want to
show for your losses. But it's possible
that the US infrastructure in the region
has taken significant damage.
If the American fifth fleet base in
Bahrain has been significantly damaged,
if not destroyed, then where do American
warships refuel? Where do they get their
supplies?
There's no other place in the region. If
all these bases are gone, where do you
go? Do you go to Guada in Pakistan? Do
you go to Karachi in Pakistan? If that
happens, Pakistan gets directly involved
and Iran can strike at them. They can
strike at Guada or Karachi.
So the longer this goes on, the more
problematic it is for the United States.
Iran has shown it can fight. It's it's
willing to fight. It has the reserves.
It has the resources. It has the drones.
It has the missiles. Its navy may have
been destroyed.
Its air force may have been destroyed.
But Trump can't take out their drone
their drones, their their missiles,
ballistic missiles.
So Iran is fighting on and even if Iran,
let's say in the future at some point in
time, runs out of drones and missiles,
they'll fight handto- hand if required.
So the US isn't in a position where it
can achieve whatever objectives they're
trying to achieve.
And Iran is hitting Israel hard
apparently. Now there's a news blackout
in Israel. So we don't know what's
happening in Israel. A little bit of
evidence comes out, trickles out from
time to time. Video evidence. Looks like
the Iranians are really hitting Israel
hard. Whether it is Telawe, whether is
whether it is Hifa, which is bad for
India,
right? So that is the situation. Now if
this continues
now the title of this video is the
question is World War II looming
see if the straight of hormon blockade
continues there's going to be mounting
pain very rapidly mounting pain for
Trump
okay he's going to be desperate to find
some resolution for the to this
and if the strikes on Israel continue
then Israel at some point in time will
say enough is enough. We can't take any
more. And Israel has other options. It
has the other weapons, nuclear weapons.
So, does Iran Israel reach a point at
some point in time in the future where
it says enough is enough and we're going
to now obliterate Iran with nuclear
weapons?
That is a possibility. I think the
possibility, the probability of Israel
using nukes is higher than the US using
nukes. But if Israel or US or whoever
uses uses nukes, that's going to be very
problematic
because both Russia and China are in a
position where they do not want Iran to
be defeated and even nuclear strikes
most likely won't defeat Iran. But that
will be a red line for everybody
including Russia and China. In that
case, Russian and Chinese support to
Iran may become pretty overt.
And if you look at the geography, Russia
isn't far from Iran. Let me show you. If
you look at the geography, Russia can
resupply Iran if if needed.
Where's Iran? It's right here. This is
Iran here. And if you go north of Iran,
you have the Caspian Sea. And right
north of the Caspian Sea, you have
Russia. The Caucasus region, Kavkas
region of Russia. Russia can easily
supply Iran with weapons, munitions,
whatever it needs if required. China
obviously is supporting Iran through
other ways through uh satellite imagery
and the Chinese GPS system, BU, etc.
And uh let's go to flight radar, shall
we?
Give me a second. Let me put flight
radar on the screen and let's see at
what's happening in the airspace in real
time.
Okay. So let's zoom out. Zoom out. Zoom
out.
There are big holes in air traffic.
There's one always over Tibet which is
which is normal because no most aircraft
don't don't overflight Tibet but there's
a major major gap in air traffic over
Iran, Iraq, Syria and northern the
northern Arabian Peninsula right all the
way to Israel. This entire airspace is
mostly empty. There's one aircraft here.
I don't know who it is and uh yeah it's
unavailable. That aircraft has taken off
from Turkier.
Well, well, well. What is Turkier doing
here? Okay. So, uh anyway, that's that's
irrelevant to our discussion. So, this
airspace is completely closed off. No
one's flying here. And there's obviously
another big gap over here. Ukraine over
here. Nobody no aircraft is flying. As
you can see on the map, these two big
gaping holes are not really far away
from each other.
You know it won't be
it's it's not uncon inconceivable that
something could happen here. See
Azarbaijan has been hit
allegedly by the Iranians. Azarbaijan is
a major supplier of oil to Israel.
If somehow Azarbaijan gets involved,
yeah, well, who knows? So uh
and and if the and if the European
nations are are draoned into the war by
the Americans then once again China
Russia may need to get involved in the
matter.
Um there is the Pakistan situation.
Apparently American military aircraft
are overflying Pakistani territory in
their in in some kind of operations
against Iraq Iran. Maybe it's
surveillance. Maybe it's reconnaissance.
Maybe it is military u
actions. So Iran is aware of this and it
has not yet taken any action visa with
Pakistan.
But uh you never know. And there's the
ongoing Pakistani war with Afghanistan
which the Pakistanis started. So there
is that issue as well. So the entire
region has become a tinder box. Okay.
and hormones it's the it's the crucial
point right now hormones is closed and
that's why it's it's causing a lot of
pain to everybody uh from the um oil
perspective energy perspective India is
seeking to get oil from other places now
obviously Russian oil and because
hormones has closed it certainly made
Russia indispensable to the world
Russian oil can fill the gap the Russian
oil that nobody was allowed to buy we
were buying it. We continued buying it.
Our purchases of Russian oil dropped
in the past couple of months to three
months but they never stopped and now we
are once again buying more Russian oil.
So we are diversifying away away from
the oil that was flowing from uh
hormones.
Uh so that's the situation. So because
Russia has suddenly become indispensable
and vital. So this war is therefore
beneficial for Russia.
And Russia will want this war to go on.
And there's another problem. The longer
this war goes on, the more this munition
stocks and weapons stocks of the
Americans and Israelis and the Europeans
will get depleted.
The European military stocks,
stocks of ammunition, munitions,
weapons, missiles, whatever are already
at a at a big low because of the ongoing
war in Ukraine. The Europeans have been
supplying UK Ukraine with all these
weapons. So Europe is down in its
supplies, in its stocks. The American
stocks are going down. The missile inter
interceptor stocks stocks apparently are
very low now whether it's Israel or the
or the US.
Apparently the first three days of the
war, the Americans used up 20% of the
global tomahawk missile supplies. Now if
this continues, this persists and
American stocks keep going lower and
lower. Hey, China is pleased, maybe
China will think I can make a move on
Taiwan. So this is connected to
everything.
Already a whole bunch of nations are
involved in the war. If a few more get
involved for whatever reason, if Turkey
gets involved, if the Americans start
using Kuresh mercenaries to fight Iran,
that will not please the Turks and they
will take some action. So everyone is
waiting for the opportunity to to take
care of business.
Kind of reminds you of the situation
right before the first world war set
off. Everybody wanted to take care of
business. Everybody was waiting for the
opportunity
and they thought it'll be short war. It
will be over by Christmas and it went on
forever. I hope we are not in staring at
that kind of situation right now. But
there is the very real possibility of a
World War II over here.
So that is my analysis of what's
happened thus far. Now let me see what
questions we have and what we can
discuss today in today's episode. Okay,
let's see. Argmittal thank you very much
sir. Argital once again thank you very
much. Argmittal is a new member. Well
thank you very much for becoming a new
member and welcome to the channel's
membership sir. Thank you. H says good
evening. Good evening to you Hush. Thank
you for being on the live stream. All
right. Vsvs says uh my Okay, this is
nothing to do with the war. My female
friend asked me why I didn't wish her
for women's day. I thought I told her
it's based on western calendar and labor
movements. So I refused to do so. Am I
in the right sir? We celebrate our own
women's day equivalent chaki puja etc.
You are absolutely right. And you know
what? If somebody celebrates something,
it doesn't mean you have to celebrate
it. If you celebrate something, does it
mean that everybody has to celebrate
whatever you are celebrating? No, it
doesn't mean that. And it's it's wrong
for for you to expect that everybody
should wish you because you are
celebrating something. Maybe they don't
celebrate it. It's their choice. It's a
free world. It's a democratic country,
right? this women's day, father's day,
mother's day, sister's day, brother's
day, I don't know what other days,
teachers day, these yoga day, why can't
every day be women's day? Tell me that
isn't don't women exist every day. So
why do you have to celebrate one day in
a year? Why? This is all nonsense. I
don't agree with this. I I don't
celebrate women's day. Let people
celebrate. Whoever who wants to
celebrate it, they are welcome to. I
they they have my best wishes. But I
don't celebrate it and I personally
don't wish anybody p women's day.
Okay. So I I am perfectly I I am in
complete agreement with you about this.
And it doesn't mean I'm trying to
disrespect women. Absolutely not. Every
day is women's day. Why do we need one
day for this? And we have our own like
you say rightfully say we were we have
our own uh equivalence shi puja naratri
so many things right. Sir
Ryik says, "How is Balenra Sha a US
asset? Explain in depth." Look, I'll
have to drag out all the evidence and
show you otherwise I can't explain. So
essentially what you have to do is go to
Twitter and find out Balancha's
activities, what he has been tweeting on
social media, posting on social media,
who he has been meeting, which
ambassador of which nation has been has
he been meeting and so on. If you do
that, you'll be able to connect the
dots. And you have to also see the
actions of Balencia
the past year or so, ever since he was
contacted by various
foreign embassies, his actions, his his
pronouncements, his statements. If you
put all of those clues together, then
the the picture becomes clear. But if
you take any of those clues
individually, you'll say, "What are you
talking about?" It's only when the
entire corpus of clues is taken together
that you can see the patterns clearly
but that will take hours to show you. So
you can do your own research.
Akshit Sharma is a new member. Thank you
very much Akit Sharma G and welcome to
the channel's membership. Thank you.
Vishal Roar says if Iran gets nuclear
bombed will that force Russia to join in
defense of Iran and also give a green
signal to Russia to do the same to
Ukraine in the future?
If Iran gets nuked, nuclear bombed by
whoever, by Israel or the US, will that
force Russia to join in the defense of
Iran? It won't force anybody to do
anything. But it is in Russia's interest
that Iran is not destroyed. It is in
Russia's interest that Iran remains
sovereign and independent. It is in
Russia's interest to ensure that Iran
does not become a US vasal
and it's Russia's interest
to ensure that Iran's oil resources do
not fall into the hands of the
Americans. Okay, these are Iran's these
are Russia's interests. Now, if Iran is
nuked,
Iran will keep fighting. But if it
degrades Iran's warf fighting
capabilities,
okay, then Russia may be
Russia may be in a position where it has
to make a choice. Shall we let Iran
slowly fall or shall we step in and help
out Iran?
So let's say somebody launches
completely hypothetical scenario. I
don't want this to happen. I'm just
saying hypothetical academic scenario.
Let's say someone one of these two
nations Israel or US uh launches let's
say five bombs nuclear bombs at Iran and
that causes significant damage and that
gives a significant philip a boost
booster to let's say Kuresh mercenaries
who are trying to um secede
from Iran take some part of Iranian
territory out of Iran if that happens
and let's say it is oil rich territory
now that will be bad for Russia it'll be
bad for Iran obviously So Russia in that
situation may perhaps seek to intervene.
So it depends on how hard does it hit
Iran. Most likely nuclear strikes also
will not stop Iran from keeping on
fighting. They'll keep on fighting.
But if if nuclear strike happens then
obviously Russia, China and all the
civilized world will stand up and
condemn this
and Russia and China may get involved in
a more um more active way in this war
especially Russia because it is close
by. Does this give a green signal to
Russia to do the same to Ukraine in the
future? Well, I suppose if you if the if
if a nuclear bomb is used here in Iran,
it gives a green signal to whoever is
nuclear bombs, then you can also do the
same thing.
But it doesn't mean Russia will use
nuclear bombs in Ukraine. Russia sees
the Ukrainian people as their as its own
people. The Ukrainian people are just as
Slavic as the Russians,
right? So, Russia is not fighting this
war in Ukraine to to kill the people of
Ukraine.
We have discussed the objectives of
Russia in great great detail hundreds of
times. So I'll not go into that. Russia
does not seek to destroy the people of
Ukraine even though that's happening
slowly. Russia has weaponized time.
Russia is dragging this war out as long
as possible, as long as is needed so
that Europe gets depleted.
But I don't think Russia needs to nuke
Ukraine in order to win the war. Russia
has chosen to go slow. It can go fast if
if it needs to.
Shantu says does China have any leverage
on the US? China has multiple forms of
leverage. A lot of the American
manufacturing happens in China. Now it
is being moved out slowly but that
leverage is there until it is completely
moved out. The second thing is China
accounts for about 95%
of the global rare earth minerals
production. So there are various parts
of the world that have rare earth mines.
Okay. rare earth elements, rare earth
metals, so on. These mines are there in
various parts of the world. But the
mining process is extremely
dirty.
It makes a mess of the environment.
Okay? It's a highly highly unclean
process. You need to use toxic chemicals
and whatnot. So no first world nation
wants to do rare earth mining in their
territory. So they've outsourced it all
to China. The Chinese understood that
this is a critical technology. It's a
critical sector.
India probably has the world's largest
rare earth resources, but we don't have
a single oper operation mind as far as I
know. Hope hopefully I'm wrong, but as
far as I know, we don't have any. The
Chinese account for that and rare earth
metals, minerals, etc. elements are used
in the most critical technologies.
Without that you can't manufacture
phones, you can't manufacture laptops,
you can't manufacture all kinds of
cutting edge equipment.
Then if China is the producer of 95% of
that, well imagine the leverage they
have with all the Americans and that's
why the Chinese are able to negotiate
negotiate with the Americans and bring
tariffs down and so on. So yes, China
does have uh leverage. Yes,
Lovish Tind says is the end goal Pax
Judai.
So there is this professor Jang right
who has suddenly become a phenomenon on
social media and uh
he I think has come out with this theory
or maybe it's an existing theory I'm not
sure and that's why this pax judika
thing has become a big big phenomenon
right now everyone's talking about it uh
is the end goal Pax Judika so you know
ask ask yourself what do you mean by pax
juda so there used to be a pax romana
pax romana means roman peace peace peace
imposed on Roman terms which means with
Roman victories. I don't know who said
it that the Romans make a wasteland and
then call it peace. Who said that the
Romans create a wasteland and call it
peace? Uh give me a second. Who said
that?
Uh give give give second. Okay. So
the Romans create a wasteland and call
it peace.
Let me try that again. The Romans create
a wasteland and call it peace.
Uh who said this? They make a desert and
call it peace. It comes from the Roman
historian Tacitus in his work agricola.
It's attributed to Kalakus,
a Caledonian chieftain. the critique of
Roman imperialism arguing that Rome
destroys lands and cultures then caused
the resulting dissolution resulting
dissolation peace. So that was Pax
Romana peace imposed. It was the
pacification of conquered peoples and
their cultures and their nations and
their kingdoms and empires through
destruction and then you call it peace.
Pax Roma today you have Pax Americana.
Now the Americans maintained the world's
peace for the past 70 80 years and now
they're launching wars everywhere. So
from that perspective, if you see this
term Pax Judea, it would probably mean
that the Jewish people conquer a big
territory and impose peace there on
their terms. That would be PAX Juda,
which essentially
is a metaphor or a euphemism for Jewish
expansion, Israeli expansion. Maybe
there are claims that Israel wants to
create a greater Israel and incorporate
the whole of the Middle East, West Asia
region in greater Israel. um that I
don't know if it's true. I mean I don't
know who comes up who has come up with
this theories. Uh is that true? Is this
the end goal? Well, I don't know. There
is no uh official statement of that kind
coming out of Israel. Yeah. Nobody, no
Israeli prime minister, no Israeli
politician that I know of has made this
claim that we need to, you know, expand
Israel and create a Pax Juda. Uh so
nobody has said that but because no one
has said it doesn't mean it's true. It
could be true hypothetically possibly
theoretically but I have no evidence of
that. All right
Jagjit says someone on X said that you
are a Russia asset
someone on X. Now what people make all
kinds of statements all kinds of
statements. How do I care? It makes no
difference to me. No difference to me
whatsoever. Listen, there are wars going
on in the world. There's Russia Ukraine.
Do I have a horse in that race? Do I
have a horse in the Russia Ukraine race?
No, I don't have a horse in the race.
There's a war going on in West Asia now.
US Israel versus Iran. Do I have a horse
in the race? I don't have a horse in the
race. My horse I have a horse. That
horse is India. That's my horse. I am
pro India. I'm an Indian asset.
I give my
truthful
analysis of how I see things. Now you
may disagree with it and you may call me
an asset of this nation that nation
because I I said things the in a way
that you didn't like perhaps maybe I was
not uh I did not praise Zalinsky enough.
That makes me a Russian asset.
Maybe I I did not condemn Russia enough.
Does that make me a Russian asset? Now
today I'm I'm saying that Israel Israel
and the US started the the the Iran war.
Iran didn't start it. Does that make me
an Iranian asset? Now
I don't think it makes me an Iranian
asset. I am no lover of any of these
countries.
Okay?
I am not biased towards biased towards
any of them.
I am only biased towards India. So I'm a
biased person. Sure. I am openly biased
towards India. Whatever I say comes from
that position and I'm nobody's asset.
I'm only India's asset. I'm the asset of
my people and the asset of my
civilization. Russia
Russia
it's our longest
standing
partner geopolitically right. So if from
that perspective if I I
if I recommend that India and Russia
should have better relations it doesn't
make me a Russian asset. It it means
that I have my nation's interest in
mind. So yeah. All right. So let people
say what they want. How does it what
difference does it make? It makes no
difference to me whatsoever. A lot of
people say nasty things on social media.
A lot of people say nasty things in the
comments over here. Maybe they're hoping
that it will hurt my feelings and lower
my morale. those people. Let me tell
you, it makes no difference to me
whatsoever. It's just funny to read your
comments. Those of you who are haters,
the minority who are haters, okay, most
of you, I'm not saying you are haters,
my viewers. But some people come once in
a while. I I I see a lot of Chinese
people typing comments in Chinese trying
to say nasty things about our country
and so on. Keep on going. Makes no
difference to me. I don't even delete
those comments or whatever. Let it be.
Okay.
Putin says Mir Shimemer said that the
long-term effect of war would be that
countries are going to have less
interest with close defense ties with
the US and if India
if Indians are smart they would have as
much distance between them and the US as
possible. What's my opinion?
Let's examine the effects of the current
war. the current Iran USIsrael versus
Iran war in which the whole Gulf region
has been dragged possibly
there are a whole bunch of nations here
in West Asia that have very close
defense ties with the US what kind of
defense ties do they have they are
dependent on the US for protection for
military protection see these nations in
let's go to the maps okay let me show
you a few things let me teach you a few
facts of life.
Okay, let's do that. Let's let's let's
learn some facts of life. If you look at
the West Asia region, okay, look look at
the entire India and West Asia region
together, then you have an ancient
civilization here, which is India.
Eastwards you have China, ancient
civilization.
Okay. In Afghanistan, Pakistan, the
whole subcontinent is Indian
civilization. Now west of India we have
a sister civilization or daughter
civilization which is Persia which is
also an ancient civilization. Now if you
go westwards and southwards we have the
Arab Arabic nations. If you see the map
if you see these Arabic nations on the
map you will see that the borders have
straight lines. Why do the borders have
a lot of strains? I'm not saying all the
lines are straight but there's a lot of
straight lines on the border. Look at
this
Saudi Arabia Yemen. So how did the
borders acquire the straight lines? It's
because these nations are artificially
created nations created by the west. Why
did the west create these nations?
Saudi, it is Arabia, right? It's Arabia.
How did it become Saudi Arabia, Saudi
Arabia? It's because the UK, the
English, the British or like Indians
like to say the Britishers, the
Britishers,
they installed the house of Saud as the
ruling family in Arabia and they named
it Saudi Arabia. And the objective of
doing the purpose of doing this was to
ensure that the house of Saud is a
client of the UK will serve British
interests and keep on uh and ensure that
the oil in the region would be sold to
the British. So the objective of the
British was to ensure that these nations
that they setting up over here these
kingdoms they will keep them well
supplied with oil and to protect these
artificial artificially elevated
families puppet families over here the
British left behind troops and garrisons
in the region
and that's how all these artificial
nations were created at various points
in time in the late 19th century and
first half of the 20th century.
So these were all client states and
eventually once the British became
irrelevant the Americans took over and
this and the entire uh arrangement
continued
right so so that's the situation I mean
look at all the straight lines on the
borders right these are all artificial
lines real borders aren't like this
so with that understood
we have to see that all these uh client
states in this region
They have American military bases on
their territory. Whether it is Bahrain,
whether it is Qatar, whether it's the
UAE, whether it is Saudi Arabia, Kuwait,
Iraq, now
Syria. Syria. Yeah. Also, all these
nations, not Yemen. So, these American
military bases were supposedly for the
protection of these nations. But when
the war happened, the Americans did not
protect anybody or they were incapable
of protecting these nations. And these
nations are being hit by Iran because
they are harboring American military
bases. And these nations are now
beginning to feel, okay, maybe it's a
wrong feeling, maybe it's a real
feeling. They're beginning to feel the
Americans aren't interested in
protecting us. They are only interested
in protecting Israel, not us, not the
Arabs. And they are getting the feeling
that these military bases, American
military bases on our territory, they
are not meant for our protection. This
is not the infrastructure of protection.
It is the infrastructure of occupation.
Okay. So these nations they actually uh
they feel betrayed right now and they
will reconsider should we really have
these closed ties with the Americans
when the Americans aren't willing to
protect us when they haven't offered us
an they haven't acted in a way that
protects us we are taking hits our
infrastructure is being burned our oil
fields are being destroyed
right they will obviously have this
grievance the question is What options?
What alternatives do they have? These
Gulf nations, they don't have any big
military-industrial complex.
They can't manufacture weapons,
munitions, arms, ammunition, aircraft,
submarines, warships,
artillery, missiles. They don't know how
to manufacture any of these things. So,
they have no choice but to be dependent
on somebody. Now, can they replace the
Americans with maybe Russia or China?
The Americans won't allow that to
happen.
And even if they try, it's going to be a
long process. So the Gulf nations are in
that dilemma right now. The Americans
were supposed to protect us. That was
the that was the deal, but they didn't
did not protect us. So this is the
immediate situation. But the long-term
effects of this is that other nations
are now going to reconsider
how they see the US. The US aura has
diminished.
US prestige has diminished.
Okay. And other nations will will think
long and hard before getting into a
relationship like the relationship the
Gulf nations have with the US. Now what
about India? India I I hope this war is
a wakeup call for India. Not to don't
take sides. Stay out of these matters.
I'm not saying India has taken sides. I
mean India kind of verbally took a side
in the beginning of the war. We refused
to you know condol the assassination of
Shri Kame and we condemned the
you know violation of the sovereignty of
the Gulf nations implicitly by Iran. So
we kind of verbally stood against Iran
and with the Gulf nations and Israel and
and the US and then India recalibrated
after three years. what kind of U-turns
are we making or maybe it's all done
strategically maybe maybe there there's
a deeper meaning behind these these uh
the way we are navigating the thing but
uh so India has to learn the lessons of
this India needs to make sure we don't
fall into the American orbit they are no
one's friends and they should not be
right they don't have to be they are an
empire an empire has no friends and
empire only has vasals
and if you vasalize yourself
at the end of the day eventually
you'll be discarded after being chewed
out.
So yeah, India should be very careful
about this. Don't find yourself in a
position, don't maneuver yourself into a
position where you have to become an
American vasa. Remain a sovereign
nation.
Okay. Sai says
uh good evening. Keeping in mind the
possibility of an oil shock due to this
war. Why do you why do you feel India is
still continuing to supply oil to
Bangladesh? Yeah, I have no idea. No
idea whatsoever. I would not supply oil
to Bangladesh.
I would not do that. But maybe there may
be some reasons that we are not aware
of. That's the only thing I can think of
because there's no logical reason to
supply oil to Bangladesh.
I mean is that
I mean you go and when there's when
there's earthquakes in Turkey you go and
help them out and the next day what you
find is that Turkey backstabs you. So my
point is why
why do these unilateral things that have
no reciprocity?
I'm not sure neighborhood first and all
these policies that we have. I I don't
know. I I can't I cannot think of any
logical reason why we are giving oil to
Bangladesh especially in a situation
where there's a oil shock in the world.
I I cannot think of a logical reason.
Maybe maybe maybe I'm not intelligent
enough. Maybe I'm just too low IQ to
understand this. But I can't think of a
reason. Honestly,
I can think of one.
Okay. Vsvs says question by Ocean Gupta.
Ocean Gupta G Kennedy tried to stop
Israel from getting the nuclear weapon
but his efforts were undone by the CIA.
Is this true? Shout out to Soldier Boy.
He truly loves India's development.
Um,
was so the question essentially is was
Ked assassinated
by the CIA because he wanted to stop
Israel from getting the nuclear weapon?
I don't know. Look, the official version
is that Kennedy was assassinated
assassinated by a lone assassin.
Obviously, that's that's a lie. That
much is clear. It's a lie. But who
assassinated Kennedy to in in in the
real world? I mean, who actually did
that? I don't know. I have my
suspicions.
I suspect it could be the US
establishment itself, which involves
which includes the CIA, of course, the
CIA, whoever else. It is possible. I
think it is the likelihood of that is
higher than any other theories in my
opinion. But why did they do it? There
must be multiple reasons for it. One of
the reasons was Kennedy not cooperating
with them during the Bay of Pigs
invasion of Cuba.
So the US military launched an invasion
of Cuba without informing the President
Kennedy
and then once the once the invasive
invading force reached Cuba they asked
for air cover. They said you know this
has happened. So Kennedy said I have
never approved it. I will not give you
air cover. And that's why the invasion
failed and there were casualties and
maybe there was a red line that was
crossed by Kennedy. That is one theory
uh about Israel. I am not aware. When
did Israel acquire nuclear weapons? I
think it was it the news came out in the
late '7s or early ' 80s because of Morai
Wanunu. Right. Mortai Wanunu. Uh but the
Israelis must have developed nuclear
weapons in the 60s or 70s. The VA
incident was 79.
the double flash over the southern
Indian Ocean there was 1979 if I am not
mistaken so they were testing nuclear
weapons then so maybe they so so that's
70s not it's not 60s Canada was killed
in 1963 right uh so I I can't say this
is all speculative
I don't have any inside information that
others don't have so it's possible but I
have no idea
bhawar says war will be going on. So
what time we Indians need to get ready
for inflation and what's your
predictions how worse it is and how
normal citizen tackle
inflation
okay
yeah so there's going to be an oil shock
if the straight of hormones closer
persists
then about 30 40 I don't know what
percentage of our oil how much oil do we
import from hormos is the question
Um
let's see let's find out what percentage
of India's oil imports come through the
straight of Hormuz
40 to 60% of India's oil imports transit
the straight of Ahmazda
well that's that's let's say 50% well
half of our oil supplies impacted
and we're going to purchase oil from
Russia we're going to purchase oil from
other countries you African nations
Nigeria etc etc etc but it's going to
still cause a shock so prices will go up
to what time be ready now be I would say
be ready right now be ready for
inflation for prices to rise anytime
um yeah if this closure persists if if
the straight of hormones is reopened in
let's say within a week's time there
won't be too much of a problem for the
world and for us for in India but if the
straight of hormones closed ure persists
even one week more two weeks more it's
going to be a major problem then prices
of everything will go up
uh so and if this goes on for 6 months
it's going to be well then the world
will re recal reroute its oil supplies
Russia will become very very prominent
and very very essentially indispensable
so the world can go on without hormones
but the the alternative will have to be
to purchase oil from Russia and Russia
has the oil
So it'll take some time for all this
rerouting to happen and re
reconfiguration to happen maybe 3 months
4 months maximum but yeah if the closure
persists for a long time
the world will will find a way to way to
cope with it.
Um yeah so I think we need to be ready
for short to medium-term problems. How
worse is it? I I hope that there is no
there are no oil shortages. India has a
84 day the media some some media outlets
say 25 days or strategic oil reserves
some say 84 days but we will we'll find
a way to import oil from Russia and
it'll be fine so so it it probably will
be a short-term issue maybe maximum 3 4
months hopefully hopefully yeah normal
citizens how should you tackle well no
Indian citizens know how to tackle these
problems we were able to survive
lockdowns so just make sure that you
know don't overconume anything and uh
for the short term deal with the higher
prices as best as we can. Yeah.
JRXna says, "What are the chances of the
US sending in ground troops now that we
have public pictures of Hummers being
transported in trucks to to Western
Iraq, eastern Iran,
to Iraq West, Iran East to uh it's
eastern Iraq, Western Iran, right? To
assist Kurdish fighters. Do we have that
Hummers? Let's see.
Kuresh fighters. Hammers. Iraq.
Let's see. Do we have something?
Hve.
Um, not sure if I could find something
there. Should I look for something on a
social media?
Should I look for it on
Twitter? Let's see. Let's go to Twitter
and let's find out if we have some
images of that coming in. Let's first uh
check that.
Um
okay,
goods Humvees.
Let's see.
Uh let's see the latest.
What do we have here? Let's see. Choban
Kuresh region Iraq.
The K borders with Iran. Kurdistan
regional government says they are only
for border protection. You never know
whether it's for border protection or
border invasion.
His clearly the Kurds.
Okay. American armor vehicles rolling
towards the Iranian border to through
Iraqi Kurdistan. US boats on the ground.
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. So, we we have
that situation going on. What does it
mean? Does it mean that we're going to
have uh American boots on the ground in
Iran? I think that's highly unlikely.
The Americans will not uh put their
soldiers their the American soldiers at
risk. The Americans will use proxies to
do this work to do this dirty work of
invading Iran. They're going to use
Kurdish mercenaries.
So the Kurds, what do the Kurds want?
The Kurds want their own homeland, a
Kuristan, a country of their own.
When the artificial nations were created
in West Asia, the white guys, the the
Europeans,
the Anglo, they forgot to create
Kurustan because they said, why create
it? How do we care? So Kurustan Kurustan
got divided between Iran, Iraq, Syria,
Turkey.
Did I miss something? Jordan. No, no,
not not Jordan. So, one nation divided,
broken into pieces and the Kurds want to
create Kurdistan and they'll be that's
what they are fighting for and if the
Americans pay their leaders, they'll
fight against the Iranians for that. So,
I think what we have those images that
we have, that's actually Kuresh fighters
going towards the Iranian border. So, I
don't see the Americans putting American
boots on the ground. They will use
proxies. They've always used proxies.
When they fought Assad,
Bashar al-Assad in Syria, they they
started the the the Syrian civil war.
They used al-Qaeda and then ISIS for
that. They do not put American boots on
the ground in Syria, right? Um
so, uh I don't see Americans sending
American troops. They will use all these
tactics. That's how I see things going.
Empty boxes.
Brahasmi cosmic id first step of Indian
education why cling to nation ideology
geography body is borrowed matter mind
is stored data then who I am really all
right sir okay
okay okay
see in Indian philosophy there is the
idea of renunciation
giving things up why possess things why
cling to possessions
why cling to pleasure
Why cling to bodily pleasures?
Why cling to the ego? Erase the ego.
Erase all desires. Erase all wants. Be
one with the universe. Brahasmi.
That is a sentiment of transcending
reality.
And that sentiment manifests itself in
renunciation in the form of renunciation
as well. Nirvana, escape the psych cycle
of birth, rebirth, all of that. So from
these perspectives, it would seem like
the Indian philosophies and Indian
traditions are all about
renouncing the world,
right? Give up the world. Don't forget
about all these unnecessary
complications. Look at higher things.
Try to be one with the cosmos.
Go to the Himalayas. meditate or try to
achieve transcendence through some other
means without going to the Himalayas but
give up all these worldly things and all
that they are superficial
right
so that's only one aspect
of our
philosophical and spiritual and
religious traditions there are other
aspects
what what's uh
virtue success liberation
virtue, success, pleasure, liberation,
all these things are important in life.
But some of the some people who are
highly evolved,
they can say body is borrowed matter,
mind is stored data, then who I am
really and who how do I care? But this
is not for most people. It's not for
ordinary people. It's for very great
people. The these sort of thoughts, they
are for very great people. For ordinary
people, you don't have to think think in
that way. for ordinary people their
geography their nation their culture
that civilization is very important.
So the point is there is a place for
everybody in our culture. For those who
are ready to renounce the world there
there are paths for them.
But for those who are not willing to
renounce the world who want to
participate vigorously in worldly
activities we have paths for them too.
So you can't have only one path for the
entire Indian education system. The
majority of people they want to
participate actively in the world. You
can ask them to say why do I care about
my body in pleasure and nation and all
geography. No that's only for highly
evolved people. That sort of thinking
for most people especially youngsters
who are just starting off in life at the
age of 5 years old. You can't tell them
to renounce the world. Right? Am I
right? So think from multiple
perspectives. An education system has to
be able to cater to all kinds of people.
Not the micro minority 0.01% of people
who are above everything.
All right.
Anand says Iran did uno reverse send
sent Hebrew text to Israelis. Did they
really? I was not aware of that but all
right. Okay.
Dolan pump says what is the reality of
Marxism? Marxism. What is Marxism?
Marxism is a socopolitical toolkit
whose sole purpose
is to ensure that a very small number of
people acquire power and stay in power
at the expense of the cannon foder.
It's a social political tool toolkit
whose sole objective is to acquire,
accumulate and preserve power.
It has all kinds of fantastic thing
things. It says it's about the uh the
the the the revolution of the
proletariat,
the dictatorship of the proletariat.
It's about the the the emancipation of
the plur proletariat. It's about the
ejection of the lumpin pluritariat and
the and the lumpin elements and the
destruction of the bourgeoisi and all
that BS it tells you
behind all that complicated verbage and
terminology
those who understand what it is know
it's about grabbing power and retaining
power and maximizing your power and the
very few people who understand this they
are the ones who typically are part of
communist parties polit bureau that is
what Marxism is it's not about equality
and all that nonsense. Nothing like
that. And it's a failure. Every single
Marxist experiment is either morphed
into something else entirely or failed
completely. For example, China. You
think it's a Marxist country? Haha.
VPS says, "We want the return of James.
James, James, my friend, James, where
are you? James is a good, good, good
man. Good English man. He gives me the
opportunity to say a lot of things that
I typically would not say. So yes,
missing James. Mr. James
JRXna says, "What are the chances of
attacks on Al Axa Mosque? Will it break
Israeli alliances with other Muslim Gulf
countries? Thoughts on Iranian missile
drop count decreasing by 90% since day
of one of the war?" Yes, I saw some
graphic somewhere. Let's see. Okay, give
me a second. Let me try and see. Let's
do this together. Let's search for this.
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Iranian missile
uh launch thing, right?
>> Iran missile count daily. Let's see.
There was a graphic I saw somewhere.
It's always nice to see visually instead
of just numbers. I mean, it's nice for
me, too. Um, is Iran losing its
momentum?
So,
Iran's barrage on the UA. Okay, this is
UAE. I'm talking about the entire war,
not just the UAE. Okay. What about this?
When was this published? This was from
March 9. This was a projection.
It was a projection uh around day five
or day six of the war or something.
March 5. Yeah. So, this is the deal.
Now, let's go back to um here.
So now I don't know how accurate these
statistics are,
but looks like things the Iranians are
are slowing down their missile attacks.
Day 1350, day 2 175, 120, 50, 40, 32,
28, etc., etc., etc. So now it's like
20ish, a handful of missiles per day.
Drone drones 294 on day 1. 541, 28, 85,
45, 38, 30, etc. Then again it's
increasing now 134 11295. If these
numbers are correct then you will say
that the Iranians are slowing down. I
mean they are reducing the number of
missile launches but now they're
increasing the number of drone launches
but not going crazy with it. Okay.
That's what it looks like from what we
are seeing there. So does it mean that
Iran is losing the war? No. It means
that Iran is being very strategic with
what it's doing. It's very very
carefully planned out. It's all
calibrated. Initially, they wanted to
exhaust the the interceptor missiles of
the Israelis and the Americans using
their old stock of ancient ballistic
missiles which they've done. And now
they're using maybe more precise and
heavier ballistic missiles with cluster
warheads.
And maybe one missile that's maybe a
two-ton missile or whatever can launch a
cluster of 50 or 60 warheads. And that's
that perhaps does as much damage as 30
missiles or something. I don't know.
Maybe that's the thing. and they
obviously want to preserve the stock
piles for a long duration war if needed.
Um so I think it is strategic. It
doesn't mean that Iran is being
defeated. Of course the Americans will
be will be trying to identify the places
from which missiles are being launched
and to take out their infrastructure. So
eventually over time as the Americans
and Israelis successfully identify more
and more of these launch sites some of
these at least will be destroyed. So
that will also cause a degradation in
Iranian capabilities capabilities to
launch missiles. So it's a combination
of various factors. But overall Iran is
so large and so well things are so well
hidden in the mountains, it's almost
impossible to take out all of their uh
launch capabilities.
So most likely this is strategic. The
Iranians are deliberately slowing
certain things down and ramping some
other things up. And it's about so it's
all planned out the way I see it. um
chances of attacks on Al Axa Mosque
which is the mosque in Jerusalem right
the dome temple thing whatever it is
yeah the the mosque in Jerusalem uh
which is built on the site of the temple
of Solomon
um chances of attacks on that well that
would be something no Islamic nation
would do right it's the second holiest
site in Islam the holiest site is Mecca
the second holiest holiest site is Al
aam mosque so I don't think any Islamic
nation would do that including Iran They
won't do that.
Um, could there be a false flag on that?
Well, I would rather not speculate about
that. And if it happens, will it break
Israeli alliances with other Muslim
countries, Gulf countries? Well, if they
decide if they if they feel Israel has
done that, it will be it won't be a nice
scenario in that case.
Sergeant Skylin says, "How do you think
this war will impact us?" Well, first of
all, it's going to cause an oil shock in
the world if the the hormones closer
continues, which means higher prices and
things like that. We will have we'll be
constrained in terms of oil imports.
We'll have to purchase oil from other
places. We'll have to ramp up our
Russian oil imports, which is good.
Well, I'm not opposed to that, right? Uh
that's one way it will impact us. And
eventually the war is going to make us
force us to make a choice of where we
stand in the world,
right? Uh so in case the Americans win
the war, they will train their focus on
India after that.
It'll be the next big project for the
Americans.
If the Americans fail in destroying Iran
and changing the regime, then American
prestige goes down. It gives India more
wiggle room in its dealings with with uh
the United States. Um
yeah, overall long-term the whole world
is fracturing.
The whole world is fracturing. Mobility
is going down. Earlier you could go to
the airport tomorrow morning and fly to
which whichever country you had visas
for right you you don't have to think of
it as long as you have money or tomorrow
tomorrow I want to be in New York City.
Tomorrow I want to be in Paris. I want
to be in in Dubai. You could do it. Now
it's difficult. So lot of impact lots of
second third order impacts we're going
to see.
Rumit Mishra says if Trump loses the
midterm election will he still a
president of the US and if he loses that
will that slow down the changes in the
world order which we are seeing after
Trump came to power.
If Trump loses the midterm election he
will still be president president but he
will be a very diminished president. he
won't have the power to push legislation
through and get his things done, get,
you know, get things done the way he
wants them to be done.
So, the midterm election is critical for
Trump. And losing the midterm will be a
disaster for him. It will be disaster
for him politically. It will be disaster
for him not only within American
politics, but also within the Republican
party.
It'll diminish him significantly. uh if
he loses will that slow down the changes
in the world order we are seeing after
after he came to power to some extent
you will see some slowing down
Trump will no longer be able to be this
aggressive with tariffs he will no
longer be able to start wars whenever
the hell he feels like that feels like
doing doing starting a war so many of
these his powers will will come down and
he will have way more constraints
domestically political constraints
domestically
So yeah, it's it's important for Trump
to win this midterm election and that
hinges on the outcome of the war against
Iran. It hinges on the outcome of this
war. So this war is make or break for
Trump. It's do or die for Trump. Yeah.
Yeah.
Ashish Karna Ashish says, "Look up
China's estimate of India's brahos
count. feels India hides strength a lot
5 range is 5k feels weird when we have
seen when we have sent probes to Mars
okay let's look up what uh
Ashish says
let's see uh let us uh go to our friend
Google
and
China's estimate of India's brahos count
let's see what is the Chinese estimate
Based on 2020 reports, some Chinese
observers suggested that India might
possess up to 14,000 Brahmos missiles. A
figure widely considered far-fetched by
defense analysts. While officially the
Indian military has hundreds of missiles
deployed across all three branches, this
extremely high estimate has likely
reflected Chinese concern regarding
India's rapidly miss expanding missile
arsenal.
So some estimates are in the thousands.
Official figures often highlight
specific procurement orders. uh 200 air
launched variants in 2012. Similar order
by the navy in 2023. The high count
estimate stems from the strategic
importance of bramos as a key deterrent
and so on so forth. India's production
cap capacity is robust. BRAMOS
integration facility capable of
producing about 100 missiles per year
which is which is not enough. Um then we
have the development of the BRAOS NG
bramos 2 and so on. The high unofficial
figure of 14,000 often cited in Chinese
media is likely not representative of
the active inventory but rather an
outlier estimating the total potential
blah blah etc etc etc. Uh okay. The
Chinese estimate India is 14,000.
Best estimate. How about best estimate?
Okay. 15 to 2,000. 1500 to 2,000.
That's the best estimate. So the Chinese
say 14,000. The best estimate according
to this AI system is 1,500 to 2,000
brahos mass. So I suppose it will be
closer to look I I can't venture a
guess. My guess is as good as anybody's
guess. I don't know.
If you feel that India is hiding its
strength a lot, well, I hope you are
right. If India has more than 10,000
Brahmos missiles, I will be very pleased
because it gives India options.
Options
Agni 5 range. Let's let's check out the
range of the AGNY 5.
Agni 5 official range
um official publicly stated range of
more than 5,000 km. Well, you know what
is more than 5,000 km? More than 5,000
km could be 5,500 km. It could be 6,000
km. It could be 12,000 km. It could be
anything.
So officially we have said it's 5,000
plus kilometers maybe 5,500 maybe 6,000
mo
is the truth we don't know it's
classified
look we need to have ICBMs ICBM cap
capabilities we need to have missiles
that can reach anywhere in the world
it's very important
uh do I believe we have missiles that
can reach everywhere
we have the technology for that have we
operationalized that operation has
operationalized this technology. I don't
know for sure. Of course, we have sent
probes to Mars, but we have sent probes
to Mars using the PSLV launcher.
The Chundrean, sorry, the Mongolan,
right? Mangalan. One second.
One second. Let's find out. I think it
was it was the PSLV.
Which rocket launched the Mongolan
spacecraft?
PSLV, I think.
Yeah, it was the PSLV. Uh that was in
2013. So look, the PSLV is nothing like
a ballistic missile. It is in a sense a
ballistic missile. Sure, you can use the
PSLV, the GSLV as a ballistic missile,
but it's it's got liquid fuel. It takes
hours and hours to fill it up with fuel.
A military ballistic missile has to be
solid fueled. I mean some missiles can
be liquid fuel but that takes that makes
it cumbersome because you have to spend
a lot of time re filling the missile
with liquid fuel. If it's solid fueled
it can be easily transported. It can be
launched anytime on demand. So um PSLV
can can be used obviously as a ballistic
missile but a if we have the PSLV it
doesn't mean that we have great
ballistic missiles necessarily. Uh but
overall my point is that I am pretty
sure the AGNY 5 has a much higher range
than what is officially stated but we
are uh not reporting that so that we
don't alarm the world but whoever is
supposed to know will know about that.
Prattana says government needs to stop
worrying about its Arab friends wallet
and use LPG alternatives by Indian
companies.
DME fuel and others are very good
alternatives to LPG. What is DME fuel?
DME fuel.
What is that? Dimethile ether.
DME is an ultra clean sulfur-free
synthetic gaseous fuel. CH3 O3. Oh, very
similar to acetic acid but not quite
CH3. Okay. CH3 CO is acetic acid. This
is different of course. So this is
dimethile because dimethile okay the
chemical formula
the chemical okay dimethile ether okay
this burns without particulate matter
making it a promising lowcarbon
alternative to diesel and LPG it has a
high citane number 55 to 60 allowing for
efficient compression ignition though it
requires specialized storage due to its
low boiling point its boiling point is
minus4.8
8 Celsius.
So water has a boiling point of 100
Celsius. So water is very stable at room
temperature.
Um
this thing has a boiling point of minus
24.8. So you need to keep it
you store it in a in a pressurized form
if you want to if you want it to be
liquid. So yeah, it needs it requires
specialized storage because above -24.8
Celsius it becomes a gas and you ideally
want it to be liquid and stored in a in
a cylinder. So colorless gas, non-toxic,
non-cargenic, carcinogenic, etc.
Produced natural gas, coal, biomass
used as a diesel substitute in vehicles,
mice, trucks and buses. A cleaner
alternative to LPG for cooking and
heating. High combustion efficiency, low
no suit. Great. No nitrogen nit
emissions
requires specialized
similar to propane gas for handling and
storage. China as always as a leading
producer. They do LPG blending using DM
DME and other countries like Indonesia,
India and Japan are exploring or
implementing it. Okay. DME fuel India.
What do we have here? Do we have this in
India?
Uh it's being developed to reduce oil
imports and emissions.
Okay. IIO Kpur has done something
but what so I kur developed a DME fuel
tractor but then did anybody
commercialize that or is it just
technology demonstrator?
How is it produced?
Production. How does it how is it
produced?
uh production production indirect. So
methanol is synthesized from sin gas
carbon monoxide plus hydrogen followed
by dehydration to DME. Oh no, you can
you don't need any specialized stuff can
do it at home. So I suppose India should
certainly look into DME as a as a very
promising and very viable alternative to
LPG which we have to import from the
Gulf nations. I completely agree with
you. was not aware of DME dimethile
ether looks like it's a very promising
and very
a very viable alternative to LPG
I agree the government needs to focus on
this because you don't need uh petroleum
reserves to produce DME you can produce
it using other means yeah I agree thank
you for pointing this out sir
minqin minqinkin says Trump said war
might be over soon. Oil tanked
instantly. Is there a chance he might be
manipulating the markets? Is there a
chance Trump might be manufact man
manipulating the markets? Well, I won't
say there is a chance.
Of course, there's a chance.
Yeah. Oil tanked and now it's going up
again.
H
Yeah, there's a chance.
VSBS says question by Dal
Dalandra
give me top 10 books to understand
history look it doesn't work like that
if you want to understand history I need
to know what history do you want to know
you want to know Indian history you want
to know French history you want to know
Swiss history you want to know German
history you want to learn the history of
Australia Americas
each
part of the world will have hundreds
thousands of historical events that need
detailed analysis
But if you want 10 books, I will give
you 10 books about world history. Okay.
Will Durant series,
the story of civilization.
This is where I first learned history as
a kid.
Of course, it's not a book books for
kids, but whatever. It's an 11 volume
set of books covering both eastern and
western civilizations. These many people
will say are outdated because they were
written in the first half of the 20th
century and they also have a western
perspective but it's still an extremely
extremely useful set of books. I really
enjoyed reading reading those books. So
yeah will durant
the story of civilization.
Aksham Malhadra says will India get
involved in this war? India should not
get involved in this war and I I I think
it's unlikely that India gets involved
in this war. It's not our war. We should
stay out of it and we will most likely
hopefully stay out of it.
Developer Kapay says alternative model
to global economy from zero sum resource
fights oil gold starving innovation and
trials India startups to nonzero sum
open sandbox models of collaborating
infinite growth. I don't have any such
thing. I don't have any such model.
Look, the world is a finite world. The
resources available to humanity are
finite.
Okay. And this is what is geopolitics?
It's it's it's the competition for
resources. It's a competition for power.
It's a competition for for for for
access to resources, for control of
resources. For control of resources
resources, you need to control
territory. To control territory, you
need power. That's what geopolitics is
all about and that's what under
underpins the global economy this entire
system.
So the fights the resource fights
sometimes they become zero sum oil gold
obviously oil also now
and that is simply the way the world is
structured and why is it structured like
this because of the nature of the human
species. We are by nature an
expansionist aggressive species.
We are a warlike species.
Our entire history is a history of
conflicts.
All major historical
change has happened through warfare.
There's no peaceful change in the world.
This is just who we are as a species.
I I can propose some model but it won't
work. That's the problem. You see that's
the problem.
The major the key players see everything
from a zero sum perspective. For me to
win you must lose that sort of thing. If
you are not if you have not lost then
you will be you will remain a
competitor. This is pure game theory
basic 101 game theory 101
zero sum competition.
You know obviously you can have
cooperation cooperative games and all
but uh yeah in in geopolitics if you are
one of the big fish you will see
everything from a zero sum perspective
that if I win and you also win then
tomorrow you may seek to take my share
of the pie so therefore let me ensure
that I win in such a way that you lose
that way I remain safe
you know so that's the zero sum
perspective and that's kind of how
things are. That's that boils down to
human nature.
We know that we are dangerous to each
other. We are dangerous for each other.
We represent a danger
to each other.
Uh and that's why we have things the way
they are. Unfortunately, I don't know
what model I could propose that could
change anything.
Singh says France sending their nuclear
carrier to S.
India is nowhere near ready for world
war. France is sending their aircraft
nuclear carrier to saw state of foremost
state of foremost India is nowhere near
ready for world war. Also I want to be a
vasal of the Cha Empire where to apply
where I don't have Chava Empire
neither a Chava kingdom that's not been
in existence for about over a
millennium. So
let's see if I can do something not in
an imperial or kingdom perspective but
you know yeah maybe maybe we can create
a group of people who can do something
constructively together in certain
fields let me let me think and think
about it and if I if I have any such uh
initiatives I will let everybody know
and and everybody can apply but as of
now I don't have any such thing. Yeah.
Now uh about the question France sending
their nuclear carrier to the state of
Hormos
um maybe it's a symbolic move u the
French aircraft carrier is the shall the
goal isn't it let's see if we have any
piece of news about this
France aircraft carrier straight of
hormuz
okay do we have something France pledges
10 additional warships in the Middle
East escorts super carrier could shield
Hormos. Nobody's going to shield Hormos.
Baba
deploying about a dozen naval vessels,
including its aircraft carrier strike
group to the Mediterranean Red Sea and
potentially the Hormos region. Look, the
fact of the matter is
the most powerful aircraft carriers in
the world are the American aircraft
carriers. The Americans had an aircraft
carrier near Hormuz and then when the
footing started they moved it away
quietly because it is vulnerable.
Aircraft carriers are vulnerable. They
are liabilities.
France is not going to put its aircraft
carrier anywhere near Hormuz.
It's too precious to risk. Aircraft
carriers are liabilities.
Submarines are what really matters. So
the French are sending their aircraft
carrier in the eastern Mediterranean.
Maybe the Red Sea. Where where are these
regions? Let's let's find out. Let's
let's go to the map. Yes. Where is map?
Here is map.
>> So
see where's France? France is here. uh
they have the kudir over here which is
the Mediterranean coast and they also
have the Atlantic coast which is uh a
all that okay so we are talking about
the Mediterranean so the French I don't
know where the aircraft would be
deployed maybe Maki maybe somewhere else
but they are going to deploy it in the
eastern Mediterranean Sea which is this
region this region here this is the
eastern Mediterranean maybe perhaps they
will transit sway okay port between port
and out also the Suez Canal and maybe
the aircraft carrier will enter the uh
the Red Sea which is this this region
here the Red Sea
maybe it may come into the Gulf of Aen
or whatever so if you are in the Red Sea
you can be targeted by the Houthis
so that's also an issue and maybe the
Houthies let you pass then you come into
the Arabian Sea into the western Indian
Ocean but then you will not come close
to Horos you will stay you will stay a
reasonable distance away from Iranian
territory because the Iranians have very
powerful missiles and France doesn't
want to get involved in the war. So most
likely the French aren't going to do
much about this. This may be a symbolic
gesture more than anything else. Mimon
does does want France to be more active
proactive geopolitically but not in a in
a way that is is is damaging to French
interests.
Uh so that's the deal with France. Uh
that's that's my assessment of how
France will behave. India is nowhere
near ready for world war. I don't know
what our state of readiness is. We are
at least a we have enough readiness to
deal with Pakistan. That's what I know.
Uh about other aspects of world war. I
am not aware. The Indian military will
hopefully be ready enough. And obviously
you you are never ready enough. You
should be more ready. U you should u
yeah India needs to learn the lessons of
the Iran war and make the appropriate
changes correspondingly.
VSVS says Aijit Cha Light asks sir why
no political no other political leaders
like Putin Xi Modi Kim Jong-un etc talk
about the deep state in the US as they
have pretty good intelligence so they
must know about it my comment Putin GI
has hinted at it
you don't speak about these things
openly
okay if you are a world leader
you don't speak about these things
openly everyone knows what The truth is
that there is a deep state
but if a world leader speaks about this
their image can be they can be targeted
and mocked and ridiculed and their image
can be brought down and there can be all
kinds of vicious attacks against them.
First of all that's one category of
things that can happen. You know if if
let's say Putin speaks about the deep
state then the west will immediately
categorize him as a conspiracy theorist
and that will bring Putin's image down.
Not that Putin Putin gives a damn
barance but that that thing that's one
thing. The second thing is you want to
have good relations with the United
States. If you are the leader of a
country
whether you are the leader of Russia,
India, North Korea, Surinam, Swaziland,
Namibia, whoever you are, you want to
have good relations with the US. Now
let's say you know that the US actually
the US president doesn't mean anything
and the the nation is run by the deep
state. Even if you know it, why will you
say it? It will it will
it will create problems in your
relationship with the US. The US won't
like it. So why will you do something
that will hurt your nation's relations
with the US?
Of course, everyone knows what the truth
is, but you don't speak about it,
especially if you're a world leader.
That's how it goes in diplomacy
and international relations. All right.
Prrenav says Andaman oil fields bidding
process auction started. Let's find out.
Okay, let's see. Let's let's Google
that.
And oil fields bidding process
auction.
Uh do we have something?
The Indian government is aggressively
pushing to explore the Anaman basin for
oil and gas with several high stakes
developments occurring between late 24
early 26. Major largely unrilled
frontier with potential reserves
estimated to be significant potentially
mirroring the large scale oil discourse
in Guyana and so on and so forth so
forth. So something is happening. Uh oil
and gas block auction deadline extended
for the fourth time. Potential investors
have till May 29 of this year to submit
bids. So if any of you want to submit a
bid for drilling in the Andermans, you
have until May 29 to do that if you have
the the resources for that. Good, good,
good, good. Akash Dhar, thank you very
much, Akash G. Thank you so much.
Ammon Matei says u yeah a PDF
file wararmongering history of nation
keeps peddling uh keeps meddling in the
affairs of other nations. conducts
almost every every every war enemy
between with other nations on earth is
saying Iran is gone rogue and lunat
lunatic such irony thoughts in Russia
Iran saying Iran has gone rogue rogue
yeah
I know I know
yeah that's how that's how it is how it
is Look, this is the most powerful
nation on the planet
and they do every everything
all all the bad things everything all
the bad things you can imagine they do
and then they call other nations a bunch
of terrorists.
They say that Iran is the global state
sponsor of terrorism. Wait, have you
seen Pakistan?
What has Iran done
compared to Pakistan? Iran is nothing.
Right. So yeah, what you're saying is
true. What you're saying is absolutely
true. It's called being hypocritical.
You do everything wrong and then you
point fingers at at others and accuse
them of doing all those things and then
you destroy them for doing those things
allegedly. That's called hypocrisy.
Well, you have to earn the right to be a
hypocrite.
How do you earn the right to be a
hypocrite? By being powerful. By
acquiring power. And this nation is the
most powerful on earth. That's why they
are able to be absolutely as
hypocritical as they want. So it's a
privilege that they have and that's why
they are able to be hypocritical.
Okay. Putin says someone
on X sarcastically called you Abijit
Pravda.
He really let me find out.
Uh let me go and find out. Uh where is X
is where? Yes. X.
Let's see.
Okay. Let's let's search for that. Uh
Bit
Ravda.
Really?
Let's find out.
No, no, no. Brava, not not that.
Um,
okay.
Oh, JS.
JS.
I see
what
okay. I have no idea what people are
saying. It's interesting that someone is
uh using this. It's fine. It's okay.
It's okay. Let people say what they say.
I think it's funny.
I think it's very funny. Yes, it's very
funny. Okay. Nikil says, "Is China's
economic collapse imminent?" No, sir.
No. No. No. not imminent.
Akash Sudhar says, "What do you think of
about Professor Jang?" Look, I haven't
watched his videos in any detail
whatsoever. I've watched a couple of his
shorter clips like 10 10 12 minute
clips. What do I think? I think he's
very competent. He knows what he is
talking about. He is an expert in his
domain in domains. He I think he's a
course on game theory is something I
haven't seen the course. Game theory is
very relevant to geopolitics and even
corporate competition and so many other
things. It's it's relevant to life. Uh
so he's a game theorist. He knows his
history. He has very clear theories
about about how things are. That much I
understand. Beyond that I don't know
about uh how good and how robust his
theories are. He seems to have become a
phenomenon of late
um on on social media on on YouTube and
on the internet. But beyond that, I
don't know. I have not seen any of his
publications.
Uh that is typically what tells you how
good uh an academic or or a scholar is
the quality of their publications. I
haven't seen those. I haven't had the
time to see those. Uh let let's see.
Let's let's
try and see. Professor Jang, right?
Let's see what kind of publications does
he have.
Professor Jang.
So Janguin.
Right. So Janguin
publications
let's see what publications he has uh
research gate research works Google
scholar it's in Chinese science direct
okay let's see earn science direct his
research interests matrix nope
values mill wave really is that same
yeah jin okay wireless communication
software etc etc this looks like
engineering
electronics.
Yeah,
this looks like
um medicine. Uh is this the same Jangin?
What about this one? It's in Chinese. Um
index low complexity
spatial modulation.
Well, this is definitely not game
theory.
It's more electronics and uh
engineering. DOS is well that's computer
science
network
stuff. Um
so maybe it's the same professor Jang.
I'm not sure. Of course you can be an
expert in one field and go into another
field. That is not an issue at all. Uh
site profiles. What about this?
What's he published
case study of? Looks like he is a
multid-disciplinary researcher which is
good. I like that. I have no issue with
that. So I still haven't formed a proper
um understanding of professor Jang. I
overall I think he's a very competent
scholar. That's all I can say. Beyond
that I don't know.
VSPS says J VSVS etc. uh
what if we are giving support so that
what if we are giving support to
somebody so that that can help us do
Pakistan just a thought it's a theory
and when you do when you play such games
you have to be very careful and you have
to think about the long-term
consequences let's say hypothetically
you give support to the US in exchange
for the US giving you Pakistan
or P
But what if you give the support and
then the Americans after everything is
over refused to give you PK. Then what
do you do and they've also failed in
Iran which means Iran also is unhappy
with you. Then what do you do? So no
outcome is guaranteed. When the war
began, it looked like the Americans will
do a 48 hour war and it's over. But here
we are. The Americans are on the back
foot. Their plans have
not succeeded. Right? So uh should be
very careful when you do such things.
Uhu
says, "I admire Prime Minister Neu. How
to be like him?" Explain in brief. How
to be like Prime Minister Neu? Well,
well, multifaceted,
magnificent person.
He was excellent in so many fields and
domains.
Um
I I can't even imagine how someone can
be that magnificent.
I mean he was a scholar of history.
He was a global statesman.
He was the proponent a great proponent
of scientific temper. He was an
institution builder.
He was a freedom fighter.
He was a charming charming man.
So many things. How do you be like him?
Well either you are born with those
qualities and talents or you can't be
like him. I I suppose that's how it goes
with Prime Minister Nu. He was a once in
a century kind of magnificent man. Shuji
I I can't say how to be like him. If if
I could be I would be would that I could
but I can't. Would that I could.
Situ Kumar says sir what do you think
about G7 country's message to India to
release strategic oil reserves?
Really? Have they said that?
Let's see. G7 India strategic oil
reserves.
Did they say something? G7 stops short
of releasing oil reserves. Asks IEA to
assess something. India rules out
releasing strategic oil reserves after
IEA cools calls for cool prices.
Uh
G7 effort to trap strategic petroleum.
India says no to let's see this one
India says no to IEA's call to release
strategic oil reserves this is from
yesterday what is IEA international
energy agency uh they have an initiative
to release strategic oil reserves as
part of an effort to cool oil prices and
India is the world's third largest oil
importing and consuming nation um and we
uh we have 5 something million tons of
underground strategic reserves they are
80% full right now
and uh so we are not a member of IEA we
don't have any obligation to follow
dictats of this body and so on
so okay that's that's what it is that's
fine we are we are under no obligation
to do what they say so yeah I think it's
great
paras says you don't celebrate women's
day you must be single you wish you wish
says can you justify why India does not
need more aircraft carriers but instead
more submarines and I'm a great admirer
of yours. Um
thank you first of all for being a great
admirer. Can I justify? Well, one
justification I can show you is the
situation right now. If the if if
aircraft carriers are so useful and they
are such an overwhelming
element of military might then why are
the two American aircraft carriers not
being used in the region in the war
against Iran? Let's find out. Okay.
Which American aircraft carriers are
deployed near Iran currently?
So you have the USS Gerald Ford and the
USS Abraham Lincoln. These are two
aircraft carrier strike groups, which
means it's not just the carrier, but a
whole bunch of ships around it. These
two aircraft carrier strike groups are
operating in the region. And you may
have a third potential carrier joining
them potentially. The USS Abraham
Lincoln is is in the Arabian Gulf,
Persian Gulf. Really?
And the Gerald Ford is such station in
the Red Sea.
It's you. I cannot believe it.
Where
where is the USS Abraham Lincoln
currently deployed?
It's in the Arabian Sea near Oman. It's
not in this in the Persian Gulf. It
would be suicidal to be in the Persian
Gulf. So the point is I mean if you want
to know where exactly this is, if it's
near Oman, it means it is staying out of
harm's way. Look where is Oman?
It's somewhere of the coast of Oman. So
it's somewhere in this region. It is not
in the Gulf of Oman. It's not here
because the here you have Iran, Iranian
territory, Iranian coastline. So it's
somewhere here maybe
maybe south of Guada all the way near
Duk. See the port of Duke over here
maybe somewhere here. So it's staying
out of range of Iranian missiles. It may
still not be out of range but it's kind
of staying as far as possible as
operationally possible while still being
relevant.
Right? That's just one example. The
Americans are keeping one aircraft
carrier in the Arabian Sea, one in the
Red Sea. If aircraft carriers are so
powerful and so dangerous and so scary,
why aren't they being actively used
against Iran when Iran is doing well in
the war, right?
Aircraft carriers are incredibly
expensive. The American aircraft
carriers cost each of them costs more
than $10 billion. 10 12 13 billion each.
Okay? So that's a huge huge investment
just for one trip
and you have to then defend it because
in today's world
you can easily kill a ship using low
cost
weapons.
Let's say you use shahed drones the
Iranian drone. Okay the Iranian drone
shahed drone costs about 20 to $30,000
per piece.
20,000 $30,000 per piece. So if you have
a hundred of those drones, it's two or
three million. If you have a thousand of
those drones, it's 20 $30 million. If
you have a lack of those drones, it's
still $200, $300 million.
If you launch a swarm of drones at an
aircraft carrier, it's simply a
mathematical certainty that the aircraft
carrier and its and its strike group
will not have enough missiles beyond a
point
to target those drones. So let's say the
aircraft carrier and its strike group
have let's say 500 missiles or let's
say,000 missiles to defend the ship. But
what if you launch 1,500 drones which
are all cheap?
What happens then? You're going to
destroy the aircraft carrier. It's a
mathematical certainty.
And instead of drone, if you launch a
supersonic or hypersonic missile, you
don't need to launch a 100 or a
thousand.
Yeah. Launch 30. Launch 50. A few will
go through. If it's a hypersonic, even
if it doesn't have a warhead, it will
slice the ship into two pieces.
So these are the reasons why aircraft
carriers are essentially setting ducks
in today's 21st century context
and they are such incredibly enticing
targets big fat target slowmoving
target. You can take them out through so
many different ways. You can use a
ballistic missile to take it out. You
can use a submarine to take it out. You
don't even have to detonate the
you don't even have to use a torpedo.
You can even detonate a tactical nuke
underwater
before any of the escorts can take can
take action. There's so many ways of
destroying aircraft carriers. Submarines
invisible, scary as hell. Submarines are
far better. Okay.
Uh Kos says, "How is India slipping to
Wasalud so fast? Why Barat cooking to
Israel? The leftover of dead British
Empire. our people kicked out looks
disgraceful globally. Look, I would not
categorize India as a vasal yet. I'm
going to re-evaluate the whole situation
after this war is over. Right now, Bat
is
among the six sovereign nations in my
sovereignty list.
I have not demoted Bat to a Wasal state
yet as per my analysis. Of course, there
are concerning uh developments for sure.
Yeah, we are technologically non-s
sovereign. We are adopting American AI.
Very very very concerning.
Uh we have major sovereignty issues
in Manipur.
Foreigners have taken over half of the
state at least. So we have issues.
But I I I will do this detailed analysis
once this war is over. Right now I am
not demoting India below 1.0 0 on the
sovereignty scale right now. Not but
there are concerning issues for sure.
Yeah. About Israel, uh Mr. Modi did
visit Israel the day before the war
started, before they launched an attack
on Iran. Um yeah, that was I think uh
um well, was it a welltimed visit? I'm
not sure. Maybe it was, maybe it wasn't.
Who am I to judge? uh but there is that
and the fact that after the war started
India took a pro- US pro-Israel stand
that also was maybe was it necessary was
it really necessary
a proud strong self-respecting sovereign
nation would not do that ideally ideally
maybe there are constraints that I'm not
aware of that only our leadership will
know
so I think we need to wait and watch for
a while let this war get over then I
will look into this.
VSVS says Paras G must understand that
Sar has been married longer than Paras G
has been alive. Who's Paris G? All
right.
Global says thoughts on John Kiryaku XCI
agent whistleblower. I have no idea
about this individual.
Look, if somebody says comes on social
media and says I am a XCI agent,
real CI real XCI agents don't do that.
And if he actually is an XCI agent,
maybe he's part of a psychological
operation, SCOP. So that's what I'm
saying. I don't know the guy. I haven't
watched this video, so I have no idea.
But I've heard of this this name over
and over again.
I I don't know the truth about this
person.
Um, Virj Sony, thank you very much
indeed. Virat Sony G, thank you very
much.
Right angle says, can we replace raw
material import from China to North
Korea?
North Korea. North Korea, what does it
export? I'm not sure what it exports.
North Korea is a small country. What can
they export? No, it doesn't make sense.
You see,
uh, stick life says chances of new
supreme leader is compromised. The new
supreme leader of Iran, is he
compromised? This is the second time I'm
hearing this today. Um, maybe this is a
psychological operation. These sort of
rumors are being spread to undermine the
morale of the people of Iran, to
undermine the morale of the Iranian
leadership possibly. I personally
personally have seen no evidence that
the new supreme leader is compromised in
any way whatsoever. All right.
Mittal says, "Namaste. Following you
since 2021." Well, thank you very much
indeed. Thank you. Yeah, that's the
beginning, wasn't it? Kind of. Yeah.
Thank you. So, Iran India allowed
Iranian ship. Kab condolence. Lando
warned on China's China mistake. Does
this show India sovereignty?
See
India allowing an Iranian ship warship
to birth at an Indian port is not words
its
so is so India is sending a message to
the world not verbally but through
actual actions like I keep saying
actions matter words don't matter so
this is an actual action which shows
that India is now
showing the world. It's not pro- US or
pro-Israel. And maybe it's not pro Iran
either. It's just being neutral. If uh
if if if a neighboring country with whom
you have good relations requests for
help, you should offer it.
And of course, the Americans will be
displeased by this because they want to
destroy Iranian ships. They want to
destroy the entire Iranian navy. And we
are preventing that from happening
entirely.
preventing the the Americans from
completely destroying the Iranian navy
that will be seen by the Americans as a
unfriendly action and still we are doing
it which kind of shows that we have some
spine left
right
a state would not do that
uh the prime minister did not express
condolences on the assassination of Mr.
Kamei
but the government has done that India's
foreign secretary Mr. miss went to the
Iranian embassy and signed the book of
condolence and other officials have also
done that. So we have offered
condolences to the people of Iran. Uh
Lando I'm not sure about what Lando
thing is but overall yeah this shows
that India is has not
bowed down entirely to the US. It is not
bound bowing down it's it's
recalibrating its stance in the war and
it does show that India is a sovereign
nation. Yes, Vira Sony. Thank you very
much, Vir G. Once again, thank you.
VSVS says, I saw an As Gold clip about
latest developments in Iran war and and
from how Trump is positioning, looks
like Iran war will end very soon. What's
my belief? Uh like I said, Trump is
reaching that situation where he doesn't
have a lot of options left.
U his critical vulnerability is domestic
political opinion
the opinion of the MAGA voters make
America great again that movement his
core voting base his core voter base his
core uh vote bank
they want victory and they want low gas
prices gas means gasolate which means
petrol they don't want to face high
prices and all that if Trump loses
control of the situation and the prices
start escalating
They will lose their trust and belief in
Trump. If Trump isn't able to secure a
victory, military victory over Iran,
well, that that diminishes American
prestige and that diminishes Trump's
standing in the world, stature in the
world, including domestically.
Eventually, the truth about the casualty
numbers will come out. American
casualties or how many they are saying
there are six or seven people dead thus
far, which is obviously a makebelieve
number. Nobody nobody believes that. So
what is the actual damage the American
military has taken? We don't know right
now. Everything is being suppressed.
What's the damage Israel has taken? So
when the truth eventually comes out, um
it will be bad for Trump because this
has not gone the way he expected.
So Trump has two or three options. One
option is take the war to the next level
and obliterate Iran. But do you have the
capability to do that? Iran will keep
fighting. So you can't inflict a
military defeat on Iran. Then the option
is you either change the goalposts and
say that I have achieved my objectives
and you walk out which makes you look
like a fool
or you go for a land invasion boots on
the ground which is suicidal. Trump
doesn't have good options. The best
option he has is to somehow declare
victory that we killed Kame and we
defeated we destroyed their nuclear
facilities again and we destroy we
well they can't demonstrabably say that
they have destroyed Iran's ballistic
missile capabilities. So you have to
claim some kind of victory and walk out.
If that happens the war is over but will
Isra agree to that?
Will Israel agree to that? That's a big
question. Israel will not be satisfied
with the war ending at this stage.
Israel has taken tremendous damage. They
want payback for that.
And if Israel is
not willing to end the war, well, I
think events have shown us that Trump
can't do a thing about that. Then he
can't leave the war. So, it looks like
Trump is trapped.
So either Trump takes the bitter pill
and ignores Israel and just says that
you know what I have won the war we
achieved our objectives and walk out but
no one will believe him but that's I
think that's the best option for Trump
because as long as his hormones remains
closed things will go from bad to worse
um so if Trump is willing to swallow
that bitter pill
in that case the war could end soon
otherwise it can it'll go on for
It has the potential to go on for years.
Yeah.
Mohit bud says rahav equal to Muhammad
knows. Exactly. Exactly. Yeah.
Mittal says if US vasal of Israel is
Israel powerful than India
baba if US is a vasal of Israel, Israel
is more powerful than India. It is the
most powerful nation in the world. Then
if Israel's vasal is the US
hypothetically
then Israel is the most powerful nation
in the entire universe. Forget about
India the whole universe if that is the
case.
Uh Rahuli says in a hypothetical world
war scenario is India prepared deep dive
deep dive
hypothetical world war is India prepared
in a hypothetical world war II nobody's
properly prepared when World War I
happened nobody was prepared for that
war to go that deep and world war I
started nobody was prepared for what was
going to come nobody's prepared when
World War II actually starts the the
question is who will prepare the fastest
and who will adapt the fastest right now
nobody knows how the war could go. So
I'm I'm not sure if India is prepared.
But how adaptable is India is the is the
real question. Okay. And for that we
have to see whether India can very
quickly uh take learn the lessons of the
war in Iran and adapt accordingly.
Sachdev Satyijit says the US was able to
reverse engineer Iran's Shahed drones.
Why hasn't India invested in reverse
engineering these drones? They can be
used to deplete the enemy's air defense
interceptor missiles. So the US was able
to acquire one or two Iranian drones
that had not exploded or whatever or
they were able to acquire spare parts or
whatever from exploded drones and based
on that I think they they one of the
drones failed or something and they were
able to recover it mostly undamaged or
with not major damage and they were able
to open it up and pull out the guts and
all that and they were able to reverse
engineer that the Americans. So the
question is why hasn't India done that?
Well, first of all, we don't have a
sample.
We don't have a drone, Shahed drone that
we have access to that we can reverse
engineer. And secondly, why do you need
to reverse engineer that? Why don't you
produce your own drone that has the same
characteristics and same behavior,
right? Is it so hard? Don't we have
engineers in this country? So, India has
come up with something. An Indian
company startup or whatever has come up
with the shishnag drone which looks like
the shah drone. Shishnag drone.
Oh, come on ma'am.
Shishnag drone drone. Okay. Shishna 15
is an advanced indigenous longrange
swarming kamic as a drone loitering
munition developed by Bengaluru based
startup new space research and
technologies designed for the Indian
armed forces. It's engineered to
penetrate contested airspace, overwhelm
enemy air defenses and strike high value
targets. Okay. The range is 1,00 to,200
km. Carries a 25 to 40 kilogram warhead.
Five more than 5 hours of flight time.
uh uses AI powered technology to operate
in coordinated autonomous network
clusters allowing them to evade defenses
and act together capable of operating in
GPS denied environments using visual
navigation systems, a delta wing
configuration and so on. What's it look
like? What's it look like? Looks like
this. It looks kind of like the Shahed.
Yes. Uh project KHL. I don't know what
project Kal is, but this is the Shishnak
drone which well looks has the same kind
of configuration as the Shahed. Uh now
let's find out what it costs.
Estimated cost per unit.
Um it's project it's designed to be in
the same class as the Iranian Shahed 136
which is an estimated cost of 20 to
$50,000 per unit. So we don't know what
the Indian drone's cost is but it is the
same category same class of drone and uh
so if it is a good drone induct that in
the lacks that's what we India should do
so we don't need to reverse engineer
anything we can we just use our own
drones which are which have the same
characteristics and capabilities
vs says just stating that India has won
the world cup well congratulations to
all Indians on this great victory we
retained the world cup uh India had won
the world up last year in 2025 when Suri
Kumar Yadav took that great catch on the
boundary. Uh
was it David Miller right? Yeah. Uh
yeah. So India won last year and this
year India retained the World Cup in the
final by winning the final in an
overwhelming fashion. So congratulations
to everybody. Great. It's becoming
routine, right? As it should be. Great.
Hardik Jooshi says, "American deep state
strategy inflict damage on Iran to
achieve temporary American objectives,
then Trump gets impeached in midterm
elections." Well, I don't know about
that. You don't get a president cannot
get impeached in midterm elections.
His party can lose the midterm
elections. Impeachment is a separate
process.
Midterm elections aren't about
impeaching anybody.
Okay? So, he doesn't get impeached in
the midterm elections.
He can his party the Republican party
can possibly be defeated in the midterm
elections. that will happen if there is
a disaster in the Iran war which is the
way the US well things are going which
may I mean disaster in the sense that
the Americans won't be able to achieve
their objectives
none none of their objectives
so or limited objectives but not the
full objectives they promised
um and Trump as the president is a tool
of the deep state if the deep state
exists so why will the deep state uh
destabilize or or or or or sub you know
sabotage their own tool. Of course,
there are reasons for doing that too,
but I can't think of any.
Okay, VSBs says, "I have hair like Billy
Hargo, but Akit G asks how to make them
like yours." Who's Billy Hargo?
Let's see.
Billy Hargo.
Billy Harr.
Harr Harr.
Billy Harr. Okay. Okay. You've got hair
like this. Well, I also see I never
leave my hair open, right? My hairstyle
I mean the kind of hair I have is also
similar to this. I don't have straight
straight hair like this.
My hair is more wavy and
my my hair forms locks. That's the kind
of hair I have. So, how do you make hair
like someone? Well, you either go to a a
salon, a stylist, and have it done that
way or you just enjoy the natural
hairstyle the gods gave you. All right.
All right. Conservative. Thank you very
much. Conservative G. Right angle says,
"Views on Misoram CM said Misoram was an
independent nation. I'm not aware of
this." And u
Yeah, I've not heard of this. Did the
Misoram CM say something?
Misoram's chief minister?
What happened?
Is there something in the news?
Lal Lal Duoma.
Okay, I'm not aware of this particular
piece of news. So I shall refrain from
commenting about it.
Argumal says if hypothetically China
versus US direct war outcome
it depends on what kind of war it is
direct war but is it limited war is it
full scale war you know full scale war I
expect the US to win but the way the
Americans are demonstrating their
performance in in in Iran if the
Americans are trying to defend Taiwan
will they be able to defend Taiwan I'm
not sure now not sure
yeah so can't say but if it's a
fullscale war the full might of The US
versus the full might of China. The US
still has overwhelming superiority. So
the US should win. VSVS says if we
exclude the once in a thousand years man
is Modi G the best we can do or Yogi G.
Let Mr. Modi G be done with his with his
uh leadership tenure. Then we'll see.
uh see once in a thousand years man that
that happens once in a thousand years
maybe this is not the time so who's the
best we have now I think Modi G is still
the best we have now but if you are
looking for alternatives eventually we
will need alternatives right eventually
the time comes then I don't know there
are so many potential candidates for
leadership
in India depending on which political
party you're a fan of if you are a fan
of the BJP there are multiple candidates
multiple people who may be aspiring uh
prime ministerial candidates
Uh for me perhaps Yogi G makes sense
perhaps. Perhaps most likely. Perhaps
says, "Is Russia slowly reaching its
past superpower status?" Not quite. Not
quite. Not yet. Not anytime soon.
Jas says, "Why did Mr. Modi not condemn
US attacks?
Because India wants good relations with
the US.
Every nation in the world seeks to have
good relations with the US. The US is
the world's richest and most powerful
country. If you have good relations with
them, your economy will do well and your
nation will do well. That's why nobody
wants to have bad relations with the US.
That's why Mr. Modi has not condemned US
attacks. Okay.
Ankita Kachab. Ankita G, good evening.
There are talks of many war crimes
happening in the ongoing conflict in
West Asia. Please explain.
war crimes. Well, there is the reported
use of white phosphorus
by some nations.
Uh, has it been confirmed? Let's see.
So, that's a war crime. It's it's not
allowed. The second thing is that Trump
has now claimed that the American
submarine captain had the option of uh
of sinking the the of capturing the
Iranian ship or sinking it. And he chose
to sink it because sinking is more fun.
if you had the option to capture the
ship and not kill the sailors, but you
chose to sink it and then watch the
sailors die laughing.
So yeah, that's two examples. The
bombing of an Iranian school in which
like one I don't know 150 16 each
children died, school children, that's
obviously a war crime. Double tapping
that area is is a horrible war crime.
What's a double tap operation? What's a
double tap strike? A double tap strike
is when you first target a place at this
explosion and lots of people die. Then
what happens? Naturally ambulances will
come, doctors will come, lots of people
will come to help. So you strike once,
then let everybody come. Then after 15,
20 minutes, half an hour, you strike the
same place again. So it'll cause more
people to die, those who have come to to
rescue the the injured. That's called a
double tap strike. There have been
double tap strikes. Apparently, this
Iranian school was doubletapped. So,
these are war crimes. There is the
alleged use of white phosphorus by some
countries. Let's see.
White phosphorus.
Okay. So, HRW, Human Rights Watch,
accuses Israel of illegal white
phosphorus use in Lebanon. And white
phosphorus is horrible. Okay. It it
burns till the bones.
So human rights group says Israeli
military using white phosphorus
munitions etc etc. So look this is the
sort of thing that's going on. War is
dirty.
Yeah. War is dirty. War is terrible.
The people who suffer the most in the
war are the civilians the unarmed people
and they are the ones yeah who are
mostly targeted the most. Uh so that
that's what I know of. I'm not aware of
any other potential war crimes. Am I
aware of something else? Um yeah, I'm
not aware of any others any other um
such instances. So that's what I can
tell you and I hope this obviously this
war ends at the earliest.
Kalia says if India attacks Pakistan and
China attacks Taiwan at once, what is
the US response? Could United China
Russia India block defeat America?
A United China Russia block could China
Russia India block could stand up to
America. If the three nations cooperate
and collaborate on all matters,
they could create a completely parallel
system economic system
and and the whole ecosystem
which would be totally independent of
the westernled system, the US-led
system. So if China, India, Russia,
China come together, it can certainly
happen. Yeah, we may not be able to
defeat America, but we'll be able to
stand up to them and not
have to worry about their pressure,
their threats and all that because the
three nations com are combining their
resources together and their strengths
together. So, we may not be able to
defeat America, but we'll be able to
stand stand up to them and we will not
then it will be it will not be possible
for the US to bully these three nations.
Now, the first question is if India
attacks Pakistan, China attacks everyone
at once. At the same time, what's the US
response? The US will probably
not be sure about what to do. Taiwan is
a precious resource for the US. They may
have to abandon the war in Iran and try
and defend Taiwan. India attacking
Pakistan is less of a loss for the US.
Pakistan is a disposable asset for the
US. But if India is able to defeat
Pakistan and achieve its political
military and political objectives,
that'll be a huge setback to the US.
Huge setback to the US. So if India and
China does this together at the same
time, I think the Americans will not
quite know how to respond. They'll
probably go for go for a potential
defense of Taiwan. They will probably
have to abandon the Iran war in that
situation.
They'll probably have to abandon the
Iran war.
Vicki is a new member. Thank you very
much, Vicki. And welcome to the
channel's membership.
And here we have white first for us.
JRXna says, "Israel has started using
white phosphorus in Lebanon after double
tap attacks on hospitals and schools in
in Iran since the escalation has reached
biochemical weapons. Are we close to
World War II?" No, we are still not
close to World War II. World War II kind
of situation will happen if more nations
get dragged into the war. Uh if the
Americans drag certain European nations
into the war, maybe France, Germany,
etc., maybe Poland, maybe somebody else.
If they get involved, if Turkey gets
involved,
if for some reason Russia and China also
get involved. So if you have Russia,
China, Turkey,
France, Germany, perhaps UK also
involved in the conflict which already
encompasses the whole Gulf region. Then
we are seeing the beginnings of World
War II.
Okay. And that obviously is contingent
on various developments and how things
go on various scenarios.
uh the escalation has used has reached
biochemical weapons. Well, white
phosphorus is not a biochemical weapon.
It's it's just a war crime. It's a
chemical of course. It's an element.
Phosphorus is an element. And white
phosphorus is an allotrope of
phosphorus. It's an allotrope, right?
Yeah. It's one of the forms. Uh so
that's white phosphorus and it's it's
very nasty.
Uh it burns to it burns your bones. It
burns everything.
So that's a war crime. alleged war
crime. I'm not sure. And there are
reports of Israel doing this. I don't
know if they are true or not. Maybe it's
all lies. I don't know.
And double tap attacks and all the like
like we discussed. Yeah. So, we are
still not close to World War II. World
War II may not have See, if there are
horrific war crimes
that could still be a localized war. You
have situations like that in in Africa
all the time.
The situation in Somalia, Sudan, etc.
It's always horrific war crime levels
stuff, but no one cares.
World War II means lots of nations get
involved in the same war. We are not
there yet and I hope we don't go there
yet and we don't go there at all.
VSVS says Anka Kachab Gi is an
underrated rich supporter of Chaaji.
Thank you. Thank you. Thank you. Uh
Ankita G. indeed.
Amul Desh Pandy says according to you
what steps should the government of
India take right now to strengthen
India's position in this uncertain world
or do you think they are already doing
everything right what's my thoughts
there are many things India should do
see in this uncertain world India needs
unity and cohesion
is India united and cohesive today
there are issues in society that are
dividing society
those whatever Ever
factors are causing divisions in Indian
society,
those factors should be addressed and
removed by the government of India,
especially if those are legislative and
policy matters.
That's number one. Number two, India
needs to now ramp up its military
strength. India spends what? 2% or less
of its GDP on on on military
expenditure. Let's find out
what percentage of India's GDP is
allocated to military expenditure.
Approximately 2%.
Okay.
Approximately 2%. I don't think that is
sufficient given the extremely uncertain
and volatile nature of the world right
now. I think the next 10 years India
should allocate 5% of its GDP. It may
sound extreme and we would have to with
the government may have to end the
largely ba yojanas and all those freely
schemes but hey
this is important. So I think that's
what needs to be done and India needs to
stockpile massive massive numbers of
missiles and drones. India needs to
massively expand its naval footprint
especially via submarines.
Um, India needs to well there's so many
things need to be undo. Maybe this is
where we should begin. Yeah. And we
should obviously uh have our own
sovereign AI systems and we should
become a world leader in AI and we need
our own semiconductor manufacturing too
for that eventually. So many things
Indian needs to do but mainly military
we need to first be able to guarantee
our nation's defense for that you to
militarize more much more than what what
we have today. That that's how I see it.
Fast snail says what's the relevance of
the third temple to Jews? I don't know.
I I don't know about Judaism and the
relevance of the third temple. I've
heard there some there are some
prophecies of something or the other but
I I don't know. Yeah, I am not an expert
in these matters. Sorry.
Argamal says, "Where were weas of the
USSR when we had defense pacts with the
Soviets? My cousins are Russian and they
praise Putin. Why Putin is portrayed as
a psychopath of the US?" Anyone who
comes in the way of American expansion
in the world is going to be portrayed as
an evil person. Right now, they're
saying Iran is a terrorist nation.
If you are if you stand up to the US,
you're going to be described as a
psychopath, as a terrorist, as evil, as
a child killer, as as god knows what.
That's what Trump does. Anybody whose
interests clash with the US, they're
going to be called names, very nasty
things by the Americans. So, Iran is a
terrorist nation. Putin is a psychopath
and so on. India has a dead economy
according to Trump, right? That sort of
thing. So, obviously Putin is not a
psychopath. Obviously he's not he's a
very rational man.
Uh now where were we vas of the USSR
when we had defense packed with the
Soviets? I'm not sure if we had defense
packed with the Soviets but we had a
very strong relationship with the
Soviets and obviously there was a power
asymmetry. The USSR was a global
superpower. India was just a tiny I mean
economically tiny irrelevant nation
third world dirt poor nation with a
nairobian rate of growth. So we were
nothing at the time and for the USSR
obviously India needed to be kept off of
the of the American orbit so that the
world was not so the Americans could not
encircle the USSR everywhere and that's
why the USSR had this relationship with
India and it is alleged that they used
to pay various Indian politicians you
know briefcases full of cash and so on
uh to stay on their side that sort of
thing. It is also alleged that certain
very high ranking Indian uh politicians
if the 60s7s etc uh were on the CIA
payroll that's also
possibly potentially most likely true.
So that's the game that was being
played. Were we vasals? We were not
quite vasals. We you could say we had um
a quasi alliance not an not a djour
alliance but a de facto alliance and the
power asymmetry ensured that the
relationship was unequal but it was not
a vas vasal overlord kind of
relationship where there is exploitation
of the vasal by the overlord that was
not the case India wasn't exploited
shivanch says Iran has indicated that
the straight of hormones will remain
open for Indian oil tankers and cargo
ships as well they have indicated Ed
this uh but what is India doing about
this? Is India willing to have Indian
oil tankers and cargo ships pass through
the state of see the difficulty is this
the danger is this
Iran is allowing some nations to transit
the state of Hormos the Chinese
India and maybe one or two other
nations.
So if Chinese ships pass through the
state of Hormuz, Iran will not shoot at
them and China is a very powerful
nation.
So the Americans will also not touch
Chinese ships. But if Indian ships are
passing through and the Iranians won't
destroy them, there is a possibility the
Americans will destroy those Indian
ships. So that is also something we have
to keep in mind. This is this is war.
War is a dirty business.
Okay.
Um that is one possibility India will
obviously have to keep in mind it's not
like the US is our great friend right
um yeah so Iran has indicated it will be
okay with Indian ships transiting which
is good for us but let's see how we what
we do about that
fast snail says is AIPSC one of the
reasons for the current situation AIPC
is America Israel professional
what What is AIBSC? Let's find out.
AIPSC
American Israel Public Affairs Committee
powerful bipartisan US lobbying group
founded in 1954 to protect to
strengthen, protect and promote the US
Israel relationship. It influences
policy by funding candidates, lobbying
officials and through its super PAC in
this United Democracy Project, spending
over a hundred million in 2024 to
support pro-Israel candidates and
defeated critics and so on and so forth.
So is the AIPAC one of the reasons for
the current situation?
Look, um,
a lot of people say that the AIPAC is is
incredibly powerful and they have a lot
of say in US policy, a lot of influence.
Um is it behind one of the reasons for
the current situation? Possibly. It is
possible but uh can't say for sure. It
is it is certainly a possibility.
Certainly a possibility. I mean Trump
was
who did he blame? He's been going around
blaming people now for the situation. He
blamed his son-in-law Jared Kushner
and other people. Marco Rubio for the
situation, for the war in Iran. Um yeah.
Yeah. So, Trump is right now starting
the blame game, but is he going to blame
the AIPC? I doubt it very much. Um, so I
I can't say for sure, but it's possible.
It's possible. JRX's ex CIA John Kyaku
said he had intel that Israel had told
has told Trump privately that they will
use nukes in Iran. Trustable. What can
lead to this? How will immediate 24
hours look like geopolitically? I have
no idea how 24 hours will look like. Uh
John Kiryaku, I don't know how credible
he is. Was he really an XCI agent? Or if
he really is an XCA agent, how why is he
why is he sharing CIA secrets with the
world? I I find this very suspicious.
So he says he has intel. Now, how does
he have intel
since he's ex CIA? How does he have
intel about such profound profoundly
delicate matters? I I I am super
skeptical about this uh this matter. But
logically it's possible that Iran that
Israel may be considering using nuclear
weapons. Logically it's possible like we
discussed earlier in this live stream
two two hours ago
in certain uh conditions Israel may be
tempted to use nuclear weapons and if
that's the case they may they may tell
Trump privately about it. So this is
something that's a logical possibility.
You don't need classified intelligence
to be able to discuss this. It's a
logical possibility. I am able to speak
about it. So I could also say that you
know what I am a member. I have I have
intel from raw
that Israel is considering this and they
have told Trump privately. I can make
that claim but what is the basis of my
claim? What credibility does it have?
Nothing. So so I don't I am I'm
skeptical skeptical about John Kiryaku's
claims. If this he actually has made
this claim
um what can lead to lead to this we
discussed it right certain Israeli red
lines been crossed being crossed that
can lead to a nuclear strike by Israel
if if Israel is taking too much damage
it is going on indefinitely and there is
no progress in the war in Iran is not
going down in that case Israel may
become desperate because too many people
are getting targeted and too many
buildings are going down and so on so
forth then Israel may decide possibly to
use nuclear weapons that could to the
use of nuclear weapons by Israel. How
will the immediate 24 hours look like? I
have no idea. Can say.
Okay. Nishan bags. Nishan bags says,
"Sorry to interrupt. I work in
hospitality mainly for money earning
about 20k CTC uh cost to company in
Bangalore. My real interests are tech
like robotics, AI and energy. Lately I
feel drained, exhausted
uh doing work. Is there a follow-up
question to that?
It sounds a little incomplete. What is
there a question that you have, Nishan?
Let me see if you have other questions
after that. I'm just looking into that.
I don't see any follow-up question. Uh
so,
okay. So, you have made a statement
about here that you work in hospitality
because obviously you get an income from
that. You earning 20K CDC in Bangalore.
your real interest are something else
entirely. Take like robotics, AI and
energy lately. You feel drained,
exhausted doing work. Well, if you feel
drained, exhausted, unhappy, then it
means that you are not in the right
place. And it indicates that if
possible, you should do something to
change your circumstances and move into
a field that actually gives you
satisfaction and fulfillment and a
salary. That's what this seems to be
telling you clearly.
So if the question is how should I
achieve it? Well, I don't know because I
don't know you personally. I don't know
what skills you have, what
what your educational and professional
background is like, um how old you are,
all those things. So if I knew more
details about you, I may be I would be
able I would have been able to give you
uh
um some specific advice.
uh but I'm what I can say is that look
if you're unhappy if you feel drained
exhausted doing all this hospital reary
work it's not for you then find a way to
move into a field that is better for you
right that's what I can tell you find a
way where there's a will there's a way
you have to make everything's possible
in the world you see to do that all
right the best do well
vss says a statement by the great kunglu
Mr. Creator Chavda is a secret molana.
Ask him about Islam. We will get your
answers.
Okay. It's very funny. Yes. Okay.
Uh Chenu Chiranji says, "If the US exits
the Middle East, could Iran dominate
hormones, change GCC, charge GCC transit
fees, push dolization, and speed up US
decline?" If the US exits the Middle
East and and and
packs up its military presence
in the Middle East, then the whole
balance of power changes. The US could
still keep supplying the Middle Eastern
nations with arms and ammunition and
weapons and munitions. That could
continue, but the US presence won't be
there anymore, right?
And obviously the the Gulf nations will
say that we haven't lost too much
because the Americans anyway did not
protect us. But does it mean that Iran
starts dominating hormones and charging
GCC transit fees through hormones and
all? I don't think Iran will do that.
I don't think Iran will do that.
Push dolization.
Well, Iran alone can't push push
dolization.
The the entire Gulf region has to do
that. Stop trading for oil in US
dollars. That will push dolization. Iran
alone cannot do that. Okay? Iran alone
isn't strong enough to do that.
Prunil says, "I live in Siliguri and my
city is being infiltrated by drugs. My
own friend is now an addict. This
started after COVID. Search siliguri
brown sugar." I'm so sorry to hear that.
I'm so sorry to hear that.
Siliguri brown sugar.
Uh
siliguri.
Okay. It looks like there's a there's an
ongoing issue in Siliguri.
BSF inspector held for smuggling 3 kg of
brown sugar.
The BSF is supposed to safeguard our
borders, right?
And why do they why do we have the BSF
there?
It's because Siliguri is a border
region. What border? Bangladesh.
One second.
Where's the where's the map? Okay,
here's the map.
Siliguri is a very sensitive region.
This is Siliguri.
So, it's the region between Nepal and
Bangladesh.
We have to be really our the government
of India has to be really really
vigilant in this area.
So, this is extremely unfortunate. I'm
so sorry to hear this and I hope that
the government of India will get its act
together. Why is a BSF guy being
arrested smuggling 3 kg or whatever of
brown sugar? Brown sugar is some some
kind of drug, right? Let me let me find
out what brown sugar actually is.
Brown sugar narcotic.
What is that?
What is brown sugar?
What is
What is that?
Yeah, it won't tell me. It's some kind
of narcotic, some kind of drug.
Terrible. I'm I'm so sorry to hear this,
sir.
Um, Vidhi Mana says, "Want Russia,
China,
China, KP2
get in calm Delhi down. India's
highest."
one Russia China
what's KP
not sure what KP is to get in calm daddy
down India is highest I'm not sure what
you're saying Vidi G but it's good to
see you and thank you
uh Vavat says I've heard news that US is
withdrawing Patriot missile system from
South Korea for deployment back to West
Asia does this give China room for
Taiwan if this continues it makes the
situation much more conducive for China
to consider very seriously a move on
Taiwan. I heard the US was withdrawing
its THAAD system, TH AA, terminal high
altitude area defense system from South
Korea to move it to deploy it in West
Asia. So if the US starts cannibalizing
its posture in one part of the world to
help its its act activities in Iran,
well that indicates that the US is
reaching a stage where it's it doesn't
have enough resources
which will make Xiinping rub his hands
in glee.
Yeah. So it's not yet the case that it
means China China has a green light for
Taiwan but it's very concerning for the
US if you're American.
Chetun says are Indian communists good
if they come to power. I don't discuss
Indian politics so I shall not comment
about this matter but
I think my viewers know where I stand on
this matter.
Gallor says the the Juan de Fuka plate
and North American plate experiencing
abnormal episodic tremors and slip
events for some time. Looks like a RTOR
9 plus is pretty close. Any way to game
this? I don't know how to game tectonic
activity.
Uh there is no
known I don't I don't know of any
technology that we have that can help us
harness tectonic activity. Tectonic
activity is highly unpredictable. We
know what the where the fault lines lie
where we know which tectonic fault lines
are more active compared to the other
ones. We know where the ring of f fire
lies and so on. But when and where will
the with the next earthquake located? We
don't really know. We we can't predict
that. And uh there's no way to harness
that energy which is tremendous energy
but there's no way to harness that if if
that's what you mean by by gaming it. Um
so yeah there's no way to game it that I
know of that I know of. Hu fuka plate
and North American plate. Let's let's
find out where this Juan Fuka plate is.
Juan fuka plate
plate plate
plate.
Okay. So if you look at the image images
Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay. Okay.
Right. Right. Okay. Are are
are we seeing the prospect of the next
big one in California?
Well, I hope not. Obviously, it's it's
northern North America, but okay. Yeah,
I'm not aware of any way of gaming it,
unfortunately.
Putin says, "Views increased, but still
stuck at 952K YouTube, etc."
All right, sir. Yeah, well, it is what
it is. I don't bother with it. I don't
I'm not worried about it.
Noise says, "Charlie Cook banners in
Nagaland Christianity." I have no idea.
Really? Charlie Cook banners in
Nagaland. Why do v will char banners in
nagar? How is it relevant here? No idea.
Animeish bharati says how what is the
experience of citizens impacted by war
in their own in their country? How much
is their daily life impacted? No water,
no electricity. If you're l if you're
lucky,
if you are in a nation that's at that's
at war. And if you're lucky then maybe
you live in a region in some part of the
country where the war isn't really
visible and it's not impacting you in
that case daily life may go on mostly
okay but if the country is being
impacted by war then even if you are far
away from the war zone maybe electricity
is gone maybe there's water issues yeah
so that happens if you're in a city that
is being targeted then electricity and
water if you don't have it you're lucky
as long as you're alive and your
building is still standing so it depends
on where you are and what the situation
is sometimes there's nothing that
happens to you. Sometimes you the only
issue you face is food is is scarce but
you can acquire food somehow but there
are levels of escalation levels of
difficulty that people face depending on
where you are and how far from the war
zone and the worst thing you can face is
what happened in Dresden Dresden
firebombing which is one of the war
crimes of the of the second world war.
Yeah.
Dresden firebombing.
The bombing of Dresden. A joint British
and American aerial bombing attack on
the city of Dresden, the capital of the
German.
Uh they dropped more than 3,900 tons of
high explosive bombs and incident
devices. Up to 25,000 people were
killed. Really? Only 25,000? You kidding
me? Okay, whatever.
So, that was a horrific war crime.
So, it depends. Depends.
VSVS says, "Professor Jang made my
buddies feel confident about getting a
girlfriend after the start of his game
theory series. He's very funny and
knowledgeable for sure." Well, I'm glad.
So, does he have a series game theory
series for how to get a girlfriend?
Really good in that case. Sounds like a
cool guy.
All right. Slayer says, "Meow meow. Hail
the meow meow god from meow then. Hail
the meow god." Yes, indeed.
Messi alien says why haven't we found
anything related to Ramayan and
Mahabharat? I know you said that we
haven't done enough digging but there
should be a lot of evidence of our
history right so look look if you have
something that happened a thousand years
ago then
if that's not a city that is still lived
in
if if you have something that happened a
thousand years ago
and that
episode ended
let's say it's a battle a battle that
happened a thousand years ago okay
hypothetically
Then over time what happens is that that
battlefield gets covered with soil
because of the process of erosion the
wind brings in soil and soil deposits
accumulates and over time layers and
layers of soil build up. So if something
happened thousand years ago it's going
to be under several significant layers
of soil maybe several feet deep. If
something happened 2,000 years ago it's
going to be even deeper. So that's why
when we do archaeology we have to dig
underground.
Okay. So if let's say
let's say one of the candidate dates of
the Mahabharat is let's say 3,000
something BC. So that's about 5,000
years before today.
So imagine how deep those archaeological
artifacts are going to be under the
ground. For that you have to do digging
archaeology.
Ramayan predates the Mahabharat.
Maybe it's 7,000 years old. I'm just
giving a hypothetical date. Okay, I'm
not claiming I know what the date is. So
then it's going to be even deeper.
Now the good thing is we know the
locations because the locations still
have the same names because India is a
place where people have lived forever
essentially. So the same places still
have the same names. So for the
Mahabharat we have names like Indraat
Indraat today which is in Delhi in Dilli
Indraat Indraat
it's the place is still there
but nobody has bothered to dig.
So it's not like you're going to find
things artifacts sitting on the floor.
You're going to have to actively dig in
the right places. Only then you find
stuff. You see that is the issue. That
is the issue. And and one example is the
accidental discovery of Duara
which again was underwater.
It was underwater right and we have this
story from the Mahabarat that the city
of Dara got submerged because of a
tectonic event a massive earthquake
because western Gujat is prone to
earthquakes.
So Arjun goes to Dar to visit the city
and he sees that he experiences this
horrible earthquake and the entire city
is swallowed under swallowed by the
ocean. it it is submerged. That's the
story. And today we have a city of Dara
in western India in Gujarat. So then the
story then the story must be a myth,
right? Until an archaeologist Dr. SR
decided to see what is off the coast of
the city of Dara. Is there something
there? And he finds an entire submerged
city. So clearly that so-called myth was
the truth. Exactly what is written in
the Mahabharat we found there. So that
way we know the places where you should
find ar archaeological evidence but
nobody is bothered to do that and that
is the issue. That's why I say that
without digging we'll find nothing. We
don't find uh evidence just strewed
around on the on the ground anywhere.
It's going to be all underground. It's
going to be all all buried several feet
down maybe tens of feet down. That's the
issue.
Alerut Kumar says when can India make
overseas territories or colonies far in
the future I mean maybe medium-term
future when India becomes more powerful
not right now. India is not powerful
enough right now. In the future for that
India will have to become more powerful
than what it is right now.
Suri says is Prime Minister Modi a CI
asset like XPM Majai? I don't believe
that at all. I'm saying about Prime
Minister Modi. I do not believe Prime
Minister Modi is an asset of any other
nation. I don't believe that. I would
rather not comment about Mr. Muraji
Desai.
Nikita
Anesthesia says India has done rare
earths deals with Kazakhstan and
according to some US is giving us
leverage cause the need India refinery
especially for Venezuela oil. My
thoughts okay I'm not aware of this deal
with Kazakhstan. Let's find out
India rare earths Kazakhstan.
Kazakhstan.
Okay. India Kazakhstan rare earths
partnership. India is pursuing
partnerships with the Kazakhstan through
initiatives like whatever to enhance
resource security etc. Kazakhstan hold
significant reserves 15 out of 17 non
rare earth elements which are vital for
electronics and so on etc etc. Okay.
Good. I'm I'm glad we are collaborating
with Kazakhstan about this. Good. Good.
I like it. I approve of it. Right. Um
um US is giving India leverage because
they need Indian refinary for Venezuela.
Venezuelan oil. Well, there's only three
refineries in the world that can refine
Venezuelan oil. Venezuelan oil. The oil
that comes out of Venezuela
is heavy SAR crude oil. It's very thick.
It looks like tar. The tar that is used
for paving roads. It looks like tar.
It's very thick and it's got a very high
sulfur content. So, it's called heavy
SAR crude oil. That sort of oil needs a
tremendous amount of refining,
specialized refining. And most
refineries can't handle that sort of
oil. There's only three refineries in
the world that can handle various wood
and oil. One of those is in India.
Okay. So that's why India is is
well India has that advantage and the
Americans are okay with India acquiring
Venezuela oil because Venezuela is now
one of their puppets.
Anerud Kumar says who are the best
people to idolize for the Indian youth?
Shri Ram Shri Krishna don't idolize
politicians don't idolize entertainers
don't idolize cricketers
the people to idolize are Sri Ram
Krishna Chetraateshwaji Maharaj Rajendra
Chula Rajar Rajulah
Samudra Gupta Kaneshka the great
subhashchundra boss some of these people
I I would say you can certainly idolize
Right? Don't idolize politicians,
cricketers, entertainers, all these
people. Clearly, some cricketers have
admirable qualities,
but they are still cricketers. Okay? I
also am a big fan of many cricketers,
but it doesn't mean you should idolize
them. All right. Chhatanya says, "How
will the future of war evolve in the age
of AI and drones? Earlier, aircraft
carriers were seen as powerful. Now
what?"
I'll tell you aircraft carriers have not
been powerful for a very long time but
only now it is visible
and of course in the past we you not you
not most nations did not have
highquality anti-hship missiles today
aircraft carriers are sitting ducks so
yeah um so how will the future of war
evolve in the age of AI and drones it's
going to be more and more autonomous
it's going to be more and more
decentralized it's going to be more and
more drone warfare drone swarm warfare
uh missile warfare, robotic warfare,
um uh AI systems are going to control
and coordinate
drone swarms in real time using battles
integrated battle space awareness which
will come from satellites which will
come from loitering drones which which
will come from other various kinds of
sensors. So everything all sensors each
drone also will give feedback uh to the
satellite and where the command and
control uh nodes and hubs and that will
allow the the your command center and
centers to to see an integrated picture
of the battle space and then your AI
system depending on how good it is will
be able to coordinate your systems in
real time
and and uh
and u deploy them at the right right
places in the in the battlefield. So
that's the kind of scenario we're going
to have. We're going to have soon,
especially with advanced nations,
nations that have high quality AI and
how high quality uh drones, missiles,
and high quality robotics. That's how
the future of warfare looks like. And
the nations that can't adapt to this
will be left behind. And you're going to
see similar scenarios at sea. You're
going to have autonomous underwater
vehicles like submarine drones but small
not as big as the submarines smaller
ones that will operate autonomously but
maybe in coordination with with each
other they will have their own AI
systems on board they may even take kill
decisions autonomously.
So that's the kind of future we're going
to have eventually pretty soon actually.
Galler versus says Verizon routers run a
kind of DOS demon demon not on their
router though no pun intended the
professor you researched has contributed
to that horrible state of being nothing
to do with the earthwhnp
so DOS is denial distributed denial of
service so Verizon routers run a kind of
distributed denial of service demon
that's that's a job that's always on not
on their router Oh, okay. The professor
of research has contributed to that
horrible state of being. Professor Jang
Jang Jang.
Okay. Oh, yeah. I was not aware of that.
Uh, I didn't I briefly skimmed through
his work.
Um,
okay. Well, thank you for letting us
know, sir. Thank you.
Uh, Suku says, "Modi has no aura, but NU
impressed Mrs. Edwina." Well,
Mr. Modi has aura in the matters that he
is uh that are important
um for the carrying out of his duties.
Mr. Nu of course was magnificent. I mean
nobody can compare to Mr. Nu. Even
Madame Edida Mountbatan was was
impressed greatly impressed by his
magnificence. So yeah,
Swastik says what makes Yugi different
from Mr. Modi? Please explain. I don't
know. I I don't get into politics. I
will not go into this matter.
GG says Iran is Iran regime change a
detriment of Indian interest since they
now trade oil for rupees which
strengthens rupee. If they change regime
they go back to USD. If there's a regime
change in Iran they will go back to
trading in USD. They will become an
extension of US oil and economic and uh
geopolitical policy. Uh they will become
pro- US. They'll become pro Pakistan.
It's it's it's bad news for India on all
fronts.
Of course, India is no longer trading
with Iran. It's no long India is no
longer buying oil from Iran. India was
buying Iran and oil up to 2016, 2017 or
thereabouts. And then Trump said, "You
can't buy oil anymore anymore from from
Iran." So, we stopped.
Um,
but yeah, if there's a regime change in
Iran, it's it's very bad for Indian
interests. Absolutely.
Raj says, "How India stopped all drones
in operations and impossible to stop
them all?" Well, the drones the
Pakistanis were using were not the kind
of kamikaza drones the Iranians are
using. The Iranians are using very high
quality shahed drones that cost 20
$30,000 per piece. The drones the
Pakistanis were using may cost like
$3,000 a piece.
They were mainly for infiltration and
for drawing out fire from India. So So
India did not have to face the kind of
drones the Iranians are deploying. Okay.
Yeah. So that's why India was able to do
to take them all out. Godliness says
after some research I concluded Japan,
UK and Germany all three have ample
resources, technology and intelligence
to succeed but the political thought is
missing or misguided and so does in
India. Why?
See Japan, UK and Germany have one thing
in common. They are all American vasals.
Japan and Germany have been under
permanent US military occupation since
1945. Japan has more than 130 American
military bases on its territory,
permanent bases. Germany has a few, but
those that is less known to people. The
UK is just a lap dog of the UK, US
ever since Tony Blair came to power,
became prime minister. So these three
nations are American vasals.
They have technology, they have
intelligence, they have resources also,
but they have zero leadership.
Their leadership is nominal leadership.
It's not real leadership. Right? Because
they are not sovereign nations. So
that's what's missing in these nations.
So does in India. Well, India is still a
sovereign nation. India has all kinds of
other problems. India does have
leadership,
right? In Japan, you have a revolving
door prime ministership. The same thing
exists in the UK. In Germany, you have a
chancellor. I don't know what they do
the chancellors, but yeah, they exist.
In India, we actually have actual
leaders. At least right now we have an
actual leader and multiple potential
leaders in the horizon. So India is
different from these nations.
Okay. Right angle says North Korea has
largest reserves of Mago, silver, gold
and rubber. I don't know what magnesium
oxide. What is Mago? Silver sliver.
Silver gold and rubber. Okay. I'm I'm
glad they do.
Vishu says if Iran doesn't fall, is
there a chance of civil war in uh Iraq?
IQ. What's IQ? Iraq. Um,
if Iran doesn't fall,
will there be a civil war in Iraq? I
think there's in Iraq there's less of a
chance of that happening. Stick life
says Abijit Ayatra said on X that new
supreme leader could possibly be
compromised as there's deep pockets in
European banks. What do I think sir? I I
I am not aware of this. I I don't have
any information about this matter. So
yeah, don't know.
Uh IPK says SAR started at red pill now
black pill courtesy of Babuham I am not
quite black yet not there yet of course
we have issues and I'm kind of well
obviously I have been voicing
look I have been hoping a lot of reforms
and things will happen which have not
quite happened so that is obviously
frustrating but I'm not quite black yet
I yeah I would not categorize myself as
someone who is blackpilled as of now.
Okay. RTX99 army says I read I read on X
that US has lost 650 plus soldiers on
their end. Uh the US has claimed only
six have died. Maybe seven maybe
somebody died in because of illness or
whatever but in com combat six have
died. That's what they're claiming. Well
obviously that is nonsense. Nobody
believes that. Uh but how many have
actually died? We don't know. That's
mainly speculation. Um,
if you were to make an intelligence
intelligent guess,
maybe 650 makes sense, but I can't say
for sure. So, yeah, that's speculation.
But obviously, nobody believes that that
figure of six soldiers dead. That's that
nobody believes. That's a lie. User DY
etc., thank you very much, sir. Indeed.
Or ma'am, thank you. Abu Shark says,
"How good are laser air defense systems
in Israel?" No idea.
They have something called the iron beam
system.
Well, an iron if if it's a highly
effective laser system, then it should
be able to take out all the incoming
missiles, even the cluster warheads that
they have. Take out each of the
individual
uh components of the cluster if it's
good enough, if it's operational. But
looks like nothing, none of that is
happening. So, I don't know. Looks like
the laser red defense is not operational
perhaps. Don't know. Can't say.
Abi says 5-year-olds are scrolling
endlessly. My thoughts. What are my
thoughts? I think it's very unfortunate.
I think that the issue is that parents
have to work and parents are always
busy. They have to earn an income and
all that. So, they don't have the time
to take care of their kids. In India
now, we have a nuclear family system.
The the joint family system is broken
up. Even the extended nuclear family
system with with grandparents staying
with grandkids, all that is gone. That's
why there's no one to no one to take
care of kids. That's why you give your
kid an iPad and then the kid will learn
how to screw it and be hooked to it.
It's it's sad. It's unfortunate
and it's it's terrible.
Anoop says, "Thank God there is no
reservations in cricket." Well, thank
God. Indeed.
Thank God.
Aush Goyel says, "A few days ago, you
explained why USA supports Israel. Can't
India be in the same super sovereign
league by lobbying and powerful
politicians." No.
No.
Yeah. That that that lobbying will not
bring you into super sovereign league.
Lobbying is bribery. Do you understand
what lobbying is? Lobbying is bribery.
Do you think the Israelis bribe anybody?
No. That's not how it works.
Sam the Gamer says, "How to ask good
questions like did
what colonize us?
Did did something colonize us?" S do
history sessions are repetitive now? I
think geostrategy shows would be diamond
on behalf of everyone.
Are you saying history sessions are
repetitive now or are you saying these
sessions are repetitive now? See, look,
right now at least there's a global
major conflict going on right now and
I'm sure a lot of viewers have
questions about that. So, I think I I
totally hear you. Uh I'm not sure if
you're saying that history question
sessions are repetitive now or you want
history sessions now more geostrategy is
definitely
yeah
maybe I should make geost strategy
resume geost strategy episodes uh so I
hear you but right now I'm going to
focus on geopolitics at least as long as
this war lasts then we shall resume to
normal programming and geostrategy is a
very good suggestion so thank you
okay vs says you should come to luckno
my city someday. It's an amazing city
and you'll be shocked to see how
developed it is. I would love to come
there. I have never been to Lacnau. So,
yeah. Yeah.
If I get the opportunity, I would love
to come there. I mean, I could hop onto
a plane tomorrow morning and go there.
But, uh, yeah.
Yeah. I don't have that sort of freedom
that I can go wherever I feel like,
whenever I feel like. I love traveling
and it's not like I have any issues with
traveling but yeah I would if there is
some event or something in Lacnau or
something I would love to come.
So thank you for the recommendation.
Divant says good evening by what can be
his real hidden objective? Did he f up?
But who who effed up? What can be his
real hidden objective?
Who? Donald Trump
uh
Shinping
Putin somebody else I'm not sure who who
you are asking this about right I'm so
sorry
no
Rohit Mishra is a new member thank you
very much sir and welcome to the
channel's membership thank you deep
learner says you say words don't matter
only action does but then you said
earlier India had chosen a side based on
Modi's posts wasn't that misjudgment
that was not really taking a side that
was
like I said at that time India had
chosen a side verbally
not through actions if we had chosen
aside through actions we would have been
involved in the war on the side of the
US or Israel
we took the side of the US and Israel
verbally
so that doesn't really matter
precisely what I keep
precisely what I keep saying.
Mr. Modi did not offer condolences to
the people of Iran on the assassination
of the Aydah and Mr. Modi condemned the
uh territorial violations
the violations of sovereignty of the
Gulf nations which obviously was implied
about Iran. So these were verbal
that is that is taking side taking a
side verbally choosing a side verbally
but India did not take any actions
that were beneficial to either Israel or
the US or the Gulf nations
right so India verbally took a side
which is not really taking a side it's
like saying full support full support
only verbally but not doing anything to
support
Indians love to say right full support
full support support but that's only
verbal support. You're not actually
taking any action to support whoever you
claiming to support.
So those were that was
that was taking side taking aside
verbally not taking aside through action
and that doesn't really matter. That's
why India has been able to recalibrate
very easily. So, so that is it still
could be considered to be a misjudgment
perhaps taking a side verbally perhaps
but maybe it was a calculated move.
Net stat grap net stat grep says why did
nobody try to take andar from us.
I think Indonesia had had some
intentions.
I think in 65 or 71 or whichever it was
at that time Indonesia had taken the
side of Pakistan
they were supporting Pakistan
or was it 47 I don't know which year it
was but Indonesia had some designs on
the Anderman and I islands and then we
sent a warship there and then everything
ended and u it's a pretty remote
archipelago it's the middle it's in the
middle of the uh eastern Indian ocean
the so-called Bay of Bengal
pretty isolated and I think we pretty
capable of defending it that's why
nobody has done that or tried that Pande
says let us India take over world west
US is doing bad job yes sir let India
take over the world I completely
completely support what you're saying
genius in says cousin is a scientist at
BC Baba center Mumbai assigned to cut
cost and save pennies in shop floor
talent wasting That's how we aim to be
superpowered. It's very very annoying
and frustrating this sort of situation.
I know I know exactly how it is. Yeah.
Uh yeah. BRC.
So we need reforms in these things,
right? We need reforms in the education
system and the academic sector. We need
reforms in in in in
R&D
environments
all over the place. Yeah, I I agree with
you. This is very frustrating.
AU says, "Why can't US flatten Iran to
save face as superpower?" Well, the US
has been trying to flatten Yemen
for years.
Between 24 and 26, Yemen, 2024 and 26,
Yemen blockaded the street of Babal
Mandev. The Americans launched hundreds
of air strikes at Yemen, essentially
trying to flatten Yemen. But Yemen is a
mountainous territory and so on.
It's hard to flatten it. It doesn't
work.
The Yemen government, the Houthis are
still there. The Americans after
hundreds of air strikes haven't been
able to defeat them. So
if you have a flat place and if you have
cities like Baghdad and all, you can
flatten them. The Americans are trying
to flatten Thran right now, but it's not
going to work out because the resistance
is completely decentralized. Then it
doesn't work. Flattening.
Okay, AJP says, "Not sure how accurate
it is, but when wherever the US big tech
companies are going seem to be getting
targeted in some way,
US big tech companies are being
targeted. Is that what you're saying? In
some way,
wherever big US big tech companies are
going." Well, I I'm not sure of this. I
have not noticed this pattern. I'm not
aware of this.
VSVS says Vish can you ask sir for his
favorite books on far east history my
super chat of 40 failed I'm so sorry the
super chat failed the history of India's
far east manipur
uh that entire region um
um
uh I
there is a book on Assam's history by
someone
Barua, right? Assam. Assam history.
Barua. One second.
Assami's history. Buua.
Um, Assami's history. There's a book,
right? Cultural history of Assam volume
1 and a comprehensive history of this is
a good book. SL Barua, comprehensive
history of Assam. That's SL Barua. is a
cultural history of Assam volume 1 by
Buu BK. This is from 1951. I'm sure it
will be good. Let's go to a random page.
It looks like this is a good book. I am
aware of the comprehensive history of
Assam by SL Bua. It's a pretty a good
reference book. Okay. I don't know about
Okay. Assam Yandabur to partition sounds
like a good book, but I haven't read
this one. Priyam Gowami treat of
Yandaburo to partition. Okay, that so
that is about Assam. Assam is the major
the largest state in the far east of
India. When it comes to Manipur, um
well the royal chronicle of kings is
good but I'm not sure if it's available.
I'm not sure if this is available
anywhere.
Okay, it's available on the internet
archive which is interesting. This is
the royal chronicle chronicle of the
kings of Manipur going back 2,000 years.
And obviously this is in the Bengali
script which most of us can't read.
Is it available on Amazon? I would be
very surprised if it was in print. It's
not available.
So yeah, I can think of a few books but
I
about the history of Manipur. I my
sources are different.
lot of research papers and stuff. So
yeah, this this is what I can what I can
offer you. Godliness says strategic
messaging is an art for public
consumption and manipulation. This art
needs training. I am sorry to say
majority of our ex egoistic
servicemen who come on media I have no
training for this.
Um thank you for sharing your
observation sir. I shall not comment
beyond that.
Okay.
Okay. Rumit Mishra says, "Don't you
think the United Nations should fall
just like the League of Nations failed
considering current situation and the UN
is not able to stop any wars?" The UN
has become irrelevant a long time ago.
The UN's job was to maintain the peace
maintain peace on on earth and they have
failed miserably at that. But they will
not fall because they are still useful
in some way some shape or the or or the
other for some nations powerful nations
like China the US etc who have
infiltrated deep into the bureaucracy of
the UN they will continue to extract
some value out of it and that's why the
UN will not be allowed to change or to
be disbanded.
Sangur Wal has become a new member.
Thank you very much Surr Wall. Welcome
to the channel's membership.
Palavi Bansil says how to avoid
impulsive leaders like Trump
make important decision. How avoid
impulsive leader like Trump make
important decisions. When you have an
impulsive leader like Trump uh they will
make important decisions impulsively. I
don't know if they have a way of
avoiding that.
So Trump has acted that way when it
comes to tariffs,
randomly imposing various kinds of high
tariffs on on nations depending on his
mood on the day. Well, as long as it's
tariffs, you can rule it back. So that
doesn't do too much harm. But when it's
a war, that causes people to die and
that's where people like Trump can cause
a lot of damage to the world and there's
nothing we can do about it.
Abai Singh says, I read that our air
force is running out of squadron
strength. Ideally, we should have 66
squadrons and 42 at the very least.
Right now, we only have we only have 30
right now. Continued
uh continued. They just mark 1 and two
are massively behind AMCA's pipe dream
and by the time Rafals are delivered,
rest of the world would have moved on to
the sixth or seventh generation.
Yeah, we we we are quite behind in terms
of our air air force, the strength of
our air force.
We are supposed to have at least 42
squadrons, ideally 66, but we have less
than 30. I think
we are slightly better than Pakistan in
terms of number of fighter planes
which is which is a horrible
mismanagement of well the air force
right
it's it's very unfortunate and uh this
situation needs to be addressed
and there's no short-term solutions to
this
even if we decide to purchase a 100
let's say F-35s. Let's say a lot of
people like the F-35. That will take
years to deliver like decades. At least
a decade. Let's say if we decide to
purchase 200 Sukoy 57s, that will take
at least 10 15 years to deliver fully.
The meanwhile, what do we do? Big big
problem. Big problem indeed.
VSVS says 34th THG. Kindly convey to
Obijit that America may presently appear
diminished in strength. Yet let him wait
a little and he shall soon behold the
full measure of British resolve and
power. Sir, this dude is James.
James. James. If it is James, well, good
to see you, James. We shall full we
shall soon behold the full measure of
British resolve and power. Well, I look
forward to witnessing the grandeur and
splendor of British resolve and power.
Indeed, I look forward to witnessing it.
AU says, "Isn't it in China's interest
that RA works with
works we versus US? Why not?"
Yeah, China has done many things that
are not quite in line with its own
interests.
I agree. I mean the Chinese u the chi
the Chinese seem to have an issue
the kind of issue where they they regard
India as as an inferior nation
and they feel that they would dominate
India rather than work together with
India. India obviously is an inferior
nation geopolitically compared to China
in terms of hard power. India is like
1/4 of China. So China is obviously
right and we are not equals today.
Historically that's a different story.
Yeah, we are an older civilization blah
blah blah. But today we are not equals
and China probably feels that China
should dominate India and also Russia.
So China wants to have a master servant
relationship not a relationship of
cooperation as equals and that's what
has worked against China because they of
their stupid obstinate attitude. Yeah.
Okay.
Riley Roy says, "Do you think we have
enough compute and energy to be an AI
superpower?" No. Our academia is barely
funded. Yes, correct. I am an IIT
student and we don't get enough funds. I
know
we don't have enough compute. We don't
have enough energy to be an AI
superpower. A AI comput is enormously
energy intensive. It guzzles energy.
Right?
If you want to be an air superpower, we
need to really invest in nuclear,
we need to have 100 200 nuclear reactors
in the country. Why not?
Right? So, we currently don't have
enough compute or energy to be an AI
superpower. Our academia is barely
funded and the quality of academia is
garbage. It's rotten. If you're in the
IIT, you are well aware of this.
If you are in the IIT, you are well
aware of this. And I'm sorry, but this
is the situation and this needs to
change. This needs to change.
Hazy says, "Why keep US in your
sovereignty index when it's a vasal of
Israel?" Okay, I shall reconsider that
too. I shall once this war ends, let me
take a fresh take a new look at this
entire matter with a fresh set of eyes.
Let this war end. I look into this.
Field strongman says please buy LPG
cylinder under many restaurants are
closing now in India.
Okay. All right. Okay sir. Thank you for
letting everyone know.
An Divu says as energy access becomes
uncertain is it time to popularize Hobie
Baba's three-stage thorian power plan
again? Yeah and we are way behind in the
timeline.
We are barely at the cusp of stage one
and stage two.
Everything is mismanaged in India. No
ambition,
no ambition.
We should have been well into stage
three today.
India has the world's largest thorium
reserves and we are they're just sitting
idle.
So yeah, I agree. It is time to take
this up on a war footing in a time of
war.
Sugand Sugand Sugand says, "Previously I
was pro-Israel when this war started
without understanding the real Indian
interest but after the last three
episodes of Askab perception changed.
You are an Indian treasure. Sharing your
videos with my circle for better
understanding. Thank you so much sir.
Have I done something that made you from
pro-Israel to something else?"
Okay, listen. I I don't think I've
spoken that much about Israel. My
perspective is the Indian perspective.
I see everything through the lens of the
Indian national interest and uh
the way I see things
Indians should be pro- India and not pro
something else.
You may like some countries but support
only your country. When two other
countries are fighting and you like one
of them,
you don't have to support them because
you like some some things about them.
See, there's a lot to admire in Israel
about there's a lot to admire about
Israel. Okay? But this is not our war.
And we also have our own national
interests that are more aligned with
Iran actually. Okay? The survival of the
current government in Iran is is
actually important for India. If it's if
this government in Iran survives, India
will have more options and more
geopolitical leverage.
So yeah, if you understand this that you
will understand that you'll you'll
understand things better I suppose. So I
I am glad I was able to u maybe
maybe shape a little bit of your
worldview
and you are very welcome sir. You're
very welcome.
Dis says what are the backdoor deals you
think are happening which could harm
India or provide profit in near future
to India? I can't even imagine what
these backdoor deals are. Now, if you
could give some context about backdoor
deals in the US, back door deals
somewhere else.
No, I have no idea
back door deals where between the US and
Pakistan. Well, that could be a backdoor
deal. I I can't I can't imagine. I can
speculate. VSVS has gifted one
membership of the channel. Thank you so
much, VSVSG.
Susant Das says hello. What will be
Iran's reaction if Trump killed Mustafa
Kame in another strike? Does Iran
surrender or do something very very
nasty? Iran does not surrender. Iran
will continue the war even if this
current supreme leader is assassinated.
That is the resilience of Iran. This is
this that's the way the Iranians have
prepared for the war. The IRGC see
so it's like this
there are nations in which the leader is
a critical vulnerability for the nation.
If the leader is killed then the whole
nation crumbles and collapses.
An example the battle of Hastings
1066.
Harold Goodwinson, the king of England,
got an arrow in his eye. He died and the
entire government collapsed and crumbled
immediately. One guy died, the king died
and the whole government collapsed,
crumbled. End of story. In Iran,
the position of the supreme leader is
not a critical vulnerability.
The IRGC, which is the real power in in
Iran, is totally dispersed and
decentralized. Killing the supreme
leader will have no effect on Iran. They
will appoint one more. If you kill them,
kill him, they'll appoint one more.
They'll keep appointing a new supreme
leader. Or if they kill too many, the
Iranians will go for a few years without
the supreme leader. But this will not
weaken the IRGC.
Iran doesn't surrender. Trump expected
that killing
Mr. Kame would immediately cause the
surrender of Iran.
No, didn't work. But if the next supreme
leader leader is killed, then Iran could
do something very nasty and they won't
surrender.
Animeish Parati says, "Hydration
reminder. Thank you very much for that
reminder. It's been more than 3 hours,
almost three and a half hours. So,
hydration reminder, thank you."
Ah, yeah, I needed that.
Ankush Sharma photographer says if
Russia is self-sufficient why isn't it
an economic superpower because it's
sanctioned because the global economy is
controlled by the US and the US is
trying to keep Russia out of it
right so Russia has the resources
but other nations are not allowed to
trade with Russia Europe was purchasing
tremendous quantities of Russian gas
that's how the European economy was
running the European industrial industry
was
The Americans blew up Nordstream too and
they pre they stopped Europe from buying
Russian oil, Russian gas. So Russia has
the resources but the western world is
not allowed to buy those resources.
Right? And obviously Russia is is coming
out of a disaster which was the collapse
of the USSR and the destruction of
Russia's economy. So Russia is still
rising. It's still growing. Because of
these reasons it's still not an economic
superpower.
Excuse me.
Gotham says other options to launch
aircraft if not carriers ground.
Ground or carriers, right?
There's no other options.
Pratam Sony says, "Admire you lot of
admire you lot. Any specific habits to
to raise our standards?"
Excuse me.
specific habits, habits to raise your
standards.
One great habit to raise your standards
which will just make you feel better
every day and that raises your standards
is pranayam.
Pranayam Indian breath work
that will raise your standards
that gives you tremendous energy and
clarity of mind. It's great for your
lungs that raises your standards. It's a
very easy way to raise your standards.
You become a higher energy person right
away with more mental clarity and there
are specific ways of doing pranayam and
some of these are secret ways. Maybe I
shall teach you those too in the future.
All right. So yeah
says you say are an Indian they killed
early one in India something white did
to other but you know called them
American despite white made Americans.
What are you saying sir?
You say are an Indian they killed early
one in India something white did to
other but you know call them American
despite white made American super
superpower
I'm not quite sure what he was saying or
asking or stating so all right thank you
for sharing your thoughts
says US giving India only 30-day waiver
for Russian oil does that show American
pressure how should India respond also
Are Pakistan's nukes owned by the US?
Pakistan's are Pakistan's nukes are most
likely American nukes on loan to
Pakistan. They are controlled by the US,
not by Pakistan. Okay, that is my
belief.
I don't have proof for this, but I am
pretty sure these are American nukes and
not Pakistani nukes and they are
controlled by America, not Pakistan.
Now, US giving India 30-day waiver for
Russian oil. Does it show American
pressure? It shows American pressure but
it doesn't mean India will stop buying
after 30 days.
India was anyway buying Russian oil.
India had not stopped buying Russian
oil. But the Americans are pretending
like the Americans decide
India's foreign policy the contours of
of India's energy policy where India can
buy from how long India can buy from
them and so on. America decides that
that's what they're trying to convey to
the world claim to the world that we now
own India which is a lie.
Okay. So how should India respond? By
ignoring their statements. Don't don't
respond to those statements and do what
you anyway doing. That's how India
should respond. Ammon Kumar Dhanker says
what are what are all possible ways
Russia can intervene? Well, one thing
Russia can do is supply is is is provide
India provide Iran with their satellite
positioning system um access to the
satellite positioning system so that the
the Iranians can target their missiles
accurately. The Iranians are most likely
using the Chinese system, Beu system
right now. Russia can provide its system
too if required as a redundancy factor.
Uh Russia can provide satellite imaging
if they have that. China obviously has
very good spy satellites. Russia can if
required supply Iran with arms,
ammunition, munitions, whatever. Yeah.
Through the Caspian seas. So many ways
Russia can uh intervene and help Iran.
Stoic animal says, "Hypothetically,
let's assume World War II ends up with
nuclear war. What is the time-lapse of
changes we see in for the people of
India? What skills should we focus on so
our nation will be left not left behind
again?"
If we assume World War II ends up with
nuclear war,
then there's no skill you will need
because you'll be back in the stone age
if you survive.
If there's a nuclear war,
okay, there are levels of nuclear war.
If somebody decides to target only Iran,
well, that's horrible and that's sad,
but it won't destroy the world. But if
this ends up in a nuclear exchange
between Russia and the US, it's the end
of the world. at least 95% of the humans
on the planet will die when forget about
skills you are back in back to the stone
age. Uh what is the time-lapse of
changes we see for the people of India?
Time-lapse of changes what happens is
that more nations are gradually dragged
into the war. Let's say the war doesn't
get over and uh the US perhaps drags the
UK, France, Germany into the war
which then and maybe Turkey is also
directed into the war because the US is
trying to use Kuresh mercenaries. Then
Russia and China get involved.
Pakistan gets targeted by Iran. Pakistan
fights back against Iran. The America
use Pakistan. So more and more nations
get involved and eventually there's a
nuclear exchange. Well, that's that's
that's a world war, right? Uh what
skills should we focus on so our nation
does not get left behind and we have the
skills. We need to focus on reforms. We
have to focus on reforms. We to clean up
the system and we to reform every
institution and every sector. That's
what need to h that's what needs to
happen. Sir
Electric Zion says, "Does diplomacy mean
anything anymore with how the US and its
allies have been repeatedly rening on
promises of peace with nations like
Iran?" See, diplomacy does matter.
Diplomacy is still relevant. Diplomacy
is all about arm twisting behind closed
doors. It's about issuing naked open
threats behind closed doors and seeing
how much you can push somebody and how
much you can how much leverage you can
use. That's what diplomacy is. Diplomacy
is not all sophisticated behavior and
wearing nice clothes and behaving very
politely. That's only for the cameras
behind closed doors. It is the opposite
of that. Diplomacy is brutal and nasty
behind closed doors. But you don't see
that. Diplomacy is still very relevant.
But what is no longer relevant is the
the word of the Americans.
Okay.
Trump lies every day.
You can no longer take his word to be
the truth. Nobody believes Trump
anymore. Nobody believes the American
regime anymore.
So that's what's happened. America's
word doesn't mean anything anymore.
Diplomacy does does mean a lot.
Himanch Ratud says, "Want to pursue MA,
PhD history and research while
continuing government job. Could you
guide me on institutions allowing this
so my papers can go mainstream?" I I
don't know about this. I I am not in no
longer been a long time. I am not active
in the Indian education system and I am
no expert on which where to get
admissions for what degree and all. I I
don't know sir. I don't know.
I am an I am a an advocate of great
reform in the education system.
I don't know which institution will
allow you to do various things while
continuing government job. I am not
aware of this. I don't have this
information. I'm sorry about that. I'm
not the person to ask these questions.
Godliness says is tech turning people to
be more and more like Mr. Chava or do
you think they are becoming more Biden?
Thank god at least I am more like Mr.
Aanga Nathan.
Is technology turning people to be more
and more like Mr. Chava or do you think
they're becoming more Biden?
But see technology I I am I use
technology I use all all possible
technology but I don't I have not become
a slave of technology
right I don't use AI to do my thinking
for me I'm extremely careful I don't use
I don't allow AI to I don't use AI to do
my thinking for me I do my thinking AI
can be used for for finding resources
and finding links and doing you know
that sort of thing donkey work your
thinking you have to do yourself don't
start outsourcing your thinking to to AI
I think most people are doing that
most people are just outsourcing all
their mental work to AI you think for me
you give me answers and I'll do exactly
what you said that's what's happening
now so most people are becoming more and
more Biden
that's what AI is doing to people um I
must be an outlier in that matter I use
AI but I use AI for doing the donkey
work that you know that sort of thing.
Uh I don't know. Yeah. So yeah, that's
that's what's most likely happening.
Surat Singh says, "What's your thoughts
on micro black holes?" Oh, I am a huge
fan of micro black holes. Yes, I'm a
huge fan of micro black holes.
Micro black holes were most likely
produced in great abundance during the
very early epoch of our universe right
after the big bang. Uh there was most
likely based on various various models
because of quantum fluctuations.
There was most likely over production of
black holes before cosmic inflation and
also in the postinflationary epoch.
So in various scenarios you have
essentially an over production of micro
black holes in the early universe during
reheating recombination even
pre-inflation etc.
Now what happened to them is the big
question. Did they just evaporate and
die out or do they still linger around
in certain shapes and forms? And what if
they formed a stable quantized bound
states which no longer evaporate or what
if they leave behind plank scale
remnants that are stable? Many many
questions out there. So black holes
micro black holes are very I think very
relevant and they may provide answers to
many of the big questions that are still
open in cosmology and physics. So I'm a
big fan of micro black holes. Huge fan.
Walika says, "Iran has a new supreme
leader. Does a younger angrier Kame make
a post war Iran India reset harder or
impossible?"
Look, the new Kame is a younger one.
He's probably going to be angry because
his father was assassinated
and he's going to be way more hardline
than his dad
and he's going to be focused on the US
right now, of course. But whenever the
war ends and Mr. Kame is still Mr. Maj
is still the supreme leader. Let's say
how will he deal with India? How will he
deal how will he approach the India Iran
relationship is the question.
I think he
he'll be pragmatic and practical about
this.
Right? I think that he will approach the
question constructively that maybe India
said some things that Iran that Iran
doesn't like but India did not take any
actions that were detrimental to Iran's
interests. So let's take it forward
positively. India also had constraints
and hopefully the relationship improves
over time. It's already a decent
relationship. It's not like we have any
problems with Iran but hopefully the
relationship can be can be strengthened
>> because Iran is a natural ally of India,
right? So I don't think a postwar India
India Ind India Iran reset is harder or
impossible. I think the supreme leader
is elected for
certain qualities. Qualities like wisdom
and pragmatism
and if you if a if the supreme leader
has those qualities there should not be
not been any problem in taking India
Iran relations forward after the war.
JRXNS independent Kurdistan effects on
India, Russia, China, China, India,
Russia.
Well, no direct effects,
no direct effects, but the complications
will have a second order effects, third
order effects that will be relevant to
India, China, Russia. Kurdistan is in
the north and northwest and no north.
It's in the west and northeast of Iran.
Not really oilbearing regions.
So independent Kurdistan
I don't think there'll be much of an
effect on India India at least or China
China also Russia is more relevant in
the region so maybe something there
grxna says what book are you reading
right now and why well one of the books
I'm reading is 1066
it's called 1066 a history of the the
year of three battles that's one why
because it's fascinating another is I
still have that Sherlock Holmes book
sitting over there. I haven't touched it
for a while.
Yeah. And yeah, I'm always reading like
a couple of books at the same time.
Maybe more than two.
Tesus
says, "Is Modi a true leader or a
product of India's weak political
ecosystem and lower leadership
standards?"
He's the best leader we've had since 47.
That's what I'll say. Okay. He's the
best prime minister we've had since 47.
He has achieved a lot for the nation. He
has got a lot he's done a lot of work
for the nation visible measurable work
more than any other prime minister. So
from that perspective he's the best
leader we have had since 1947. That's my
view.
JXNA is a new member. Thank you very
much and welcome to the channel's
membership.
He just asks the same question again but
I just answered that. All right. Really
now Miss Patel says tell us about the
Knight's Templar still active. The
Knights Templar were a powerful group of
powerful religious group warrior
religious warriors monk warriors
um from the time of the crusades
and they were eventually destroyed. They
were all massacred. I don't remember
which king it was who massacred them. Um
and they've they they fought the
crusades
and eventually there was essentially a
coup against them and they were all
captured and killed.
Um and there are certain
religious places that are associate that
have were associated in the past with
the Knights Templar. They were after the
holy grail cup that held the blood of
Shri Christ of Mr. Christ. That's the
kind of story one hears. And there's
this chapel, this this church in
Scotland, Ireland, where is it? Rosslin
Chapel that is associated with that with
the Knights Templar. Are they still
active? Not to my not to my knowledge.
Not to my knowledge.
Shri Shray Singh Raat says, "Loved your
work with me streams. Pleased, please do
more." Oh, the work with me streams.
Well, there were like 30 people watching
it every stream. Huh? I'm not sure if it
was something that most people wanted,
but I'm glad you loved them. Thank you.
Al Kashikari says, "Hypothetically, what
happens if the US quits and leaves
Israel alone in this war?" Well, the U
the Israel gets very displeased. But if
the US just walks out and says, "Okay,
I'm done with done with the war. Done."
What happens? Can Israel fight alone?
Israel can keep fighting if they keep
getting supplies from the US.
Israel's war fighting capability depends
on them getting supplied by the US. What
supplies? Arms, ammunitions, munition,
all that ammunition, not ammunitions,
all that. America supplies the weapons
Israel uses for fighting its wars. Of
course, Israel also has its own weapons
manufacturing capabilities, but all of
but it can't take care of all of its
requirements and needs. So if the US
quits but keeps supplying Israel with
whatever it needs, Israel can keep
fighting but Israel will come under
tremendous pressure now because Iran no
longer has to fight America. It can
focus on Israel alone. So it will be
very very very very dangerous for Israel
if this happens.
Anupam Sudhakran is a new member. Thank
you very much Anupam Sudhakaran. And I
love the display picture you've got.
Chingis Khan. Welcome to the channel's
membership.
Clever Sid says, "What's the impact on
the environment because of this war?"
Disaster. The Americans have have blown
up oil
um oil deposing
and the whole sky above Thran is dark
now. Huge thick black clouds of smoke.
And when it rains, it rains oil. It's a
disaster for the environment. What
happened to carbon footprint and all
that stuff? No one cares now, right? No
one's going to talk about that now.
Past snail says, can India get the
exception like China to get a pass at
the straight of Hormuz or has it dented
relations with Iran after taking the
side of Israel? See, India only verbally
kind of took the side of Israel and the
US. India has not taken any actions
that take the side of Israel or the US.
through actions. India has actually
taken the side of Iran kind of by uh
giving shelter to an Iranian warship in
a port in an Indian port which where the
Iran ship currently currently sits and
the sailors are being accommodated in
Indian naval headquarters I mean
quarters quarters. So India has not
taken any actions
against Iran. Through actions, India has
been kind of pro- Iran slightly and Iran
has already said that India has an
exception. Indian ships can transit the
oil the straight of foremost Iran will
not target them. So India already has
that exception. Yeah.
Kishv
Kishan says if Iran manages to finish BB
BB Netanyahu what happens then? Well,
then I think if that happens, then
Israel will take very drastic action
against Iran and the war will escalate
to very dangerous levels.
Deep learner says, "Sorry, I meant to
ask, wasn't that a misjudgment on your
part when you said India chose a side
considering everything was words? No
offense." No, no offense. I said India
took chose a side verbally and I I stand
by what I said. Of course, India chose a
side verbally.
That's not a misjudgment. I I don't
think it's a mis judgment. What I said
at the time was correct. See, today we
have the benefit of hindsight. It's been
like 8 9 10 days of war. What I said on
day two or day three.
Now we have more information and maybe
things have changed completely. There
are people
who expect that what I said 5 years ago,
I should still stick to that. But hasn't
the world changed?
My analysis will be shaped by the
changing world order. What I said four
years ago, 5 years ago may not be
relevant at all today. So my analysis
was relevant 4 years ago but what I said
today is relevant for today. And what I
say today may be totally different from
what I said four years ago because the
world was different then. But people
don't understand that. They say you keep
changing your analysis.
The world is changing.
Right?
So what I said initially that India has
taken the side of has chosen a side
verbally
for practical reasons not the
ideological reasons. Well that's what
India did at the time. Now India has
recalibrated.
Maybe India thought it is misjudged. Is
that my misjudgment? No. So no it's not
a misjudgment.
Anupam Sudhakaran says namaste. Namaste
G. Doesn't the deep state have any say
in the present conflict? The deep state
is driving the conflict. Are all
decisions being made by President Trump?
Um, sure. Is he being molded into a
convenient pitch pinch bag to pin all
the blames? Well, if things go south,
he's going to be blamed for everything.
Of course, the buck stops at the top and
the official top is
the the White House.
uh the deep state is driving the
conflict.
Trump is just what we see and of course
if things go wrong they'll blame him.
Are all decisions being made by
President Trump? Well you see Marco
Rubio gave gave this quote during an
interaction with the press like three
three days into the war three or four
days into the war when asked why this
war happened. And he said that we had
knowledge that Israel was planning to
strike at Iran and we knew that if
Israel strike at Iran, Iran would strike
back at us too. So that's why we
preempted that by striking at Iran
before the Iranians could strike back at
us because we knew Israel was going to
strike them. But what if you allow
Israel to strike but you stay out of it?
Then what happens? So essentially Marco
Rubio admitted that Israel dragged the
US into the war.
So Marco Rubio admitted that the US is
powerless to stop Israel from doing
this. And when Israel gets involved into
a war, the US has to rescue them. So are
these decisions being made by President
Trump? I'm not sure. It shows that a lot
of decisions are being made by Israel
actually.
Yeah. Right.
Modern Saburai Gaming says Bangladesh
Cle Hindus denied to play cricket in
India giving Bangladesh five turns of
diesel. I don't understand what India is
doing. I don't understand.
Yeah.
Tennis India. Well, thank you very much.
Tennis India
house of discussion says will it be Asia
versus Europe World War II in Middle
East reason oil?
It's not Asia versus Europe. That's
that's a very that's not the division we
have here. We have the US and Israel
versus Iran. But along with US and
Israel, there's a number of nations,
West Asian nations, U Saudi Arabia, uh
Qatar, Bahrain, Kuwait, Iraq
and UAE, etc., who are all involved in
the war.
So, it's Asia versus Asia kind of being
driven by by outsiders. If you consider
Europe Israel to be a European nation
which it's actually not but whatever. So
it's not a split between Asia and Europe
in this form. The watch man says any
comments on the upcoming alien
disclosure by the president of the US
about also about Steven Spielberg is
also coming up with the Hollywood movie.
What a time to be alive. I am super
skeptical about this alien disclosure.
Super skeptical.
All this UFO activity and all that that
people see in some countries, I believe
it is merely super advanced technology
that the Americans have. I don't think
it's any actual aliens who are visiting
the planet. I'll be very pleased if
there's actual evidence of aliens, but
simply putting out an email that claims
there are aliens is not proof or or
publishing a document that says we met
aliens, it's not proof. Show the actual
aliens. I would like to see a podcast
with an alien.
My friend Reanir would like to do that.
I would like to say an actual alien
hard evidence, incontrovertible
evidence, not this claim. So I am very
skeptical about this.
Nishan bag says, "I am 22, XJ. Father
got cancer, no savings, working." Okay,
you're giving more more context here.
I'm 22 years old. You are exe student.
Father got cancer, no savings, working
13 14 hours. Have no strong skills yet.
I'm eager to learn. I feel stuck. Any
advice? So you are in like you said you
were interested in in in in in in
technology and things like that right
I for I don't have the yeah so you are
interested in in
technology and so on and you don't have
any skills right now so look the good
news is you just 22 you're a kid you're
just starting off
right okay right now it's you're not
happy you're working 13 14 hours a day
you don't have strong skills you're
eager to learn you feel stuck.
Well, what I would say is
spend your free time acquiring skills.
It's hard to have free time when you are
working 134 hours. So try to somehow
engineer
slightly better working hours, maybe 10
hours instead of 13, 14. That way you
can sleep eight hours and do find some
time to get to acquire skills and study
study as as as diligently as possible
and study not not academic study but
acquiring skills study. Today you can
acquire skills for free. You don't need
to you know go to college university or
whatever to acquire the skills that you
want. All the information and knowledge
best information best knowledge is
available on YouTube if you want to
learn programming if you want to learn
machine learning or machine or whatever
it is. So find find the time somehow
anyhow in the next 2 years 3 years
maximum acquire the skills you need and
then find a way to pivot. Find a way to
pivot. That's what you should do. You
just 22 you're just starting off you
don't need to be disheartened.
Okay.
Uh even if you succeed by 30 it's a
great great outcome. And the struggle
will teach you a lot that people who
have not struggled will never learn. So
what I would say is stay healthy, stay
energetic
and uh yeah just just go for it. All
right sir. All the best. I'm sorry that
you're in the situation but you can
overcome it all. All the best. Nishan
Gouibar says, "How can the West pressure
Russia if the US eases restrictions for
markets while the EU tightens them? Is
this a rift in relations or a European
move towards strategic independence?"
Um, Europe does speak seek seek more
strategic autonomy for sure. Yeah,
Europe feels constrained by the you know
by the overbearing overbearing uh
behavior of the US. The US has
reconfigured its relationship with
Europe. Yeah. NATO especi especially.
Um,
how could the West pressure if the US
eases restrictions for markets while the
EU tightens them? Well,
I'm not sure specifically what's
happening that you're talking about. US
eases restrictions for which markets and
the EU tightens restrictions for which
markets? European markets. But when it
comes to India and Europe, we have a
trade deal now and the restrictions are
being lifted significantly for India. So
sometimes the US and the EU may be at
cross purposes
and that obviously will be good for
Russia.
But that's the way things go especially
in a in a in coalitions involving lots
of countries like the EU also also NATO.
Okay. Prashan Sharma says NBC interview
with Iran foreign minister is funny.
Okay. I have not watched it and I will
not watch it here but thank you for
letting me know. I don't mind some
watching something funny. I' I'd love to
watch it. Yeah.
Tani Kaz says, "Who do you think the
terrorists are, Iran or the USA?" Well,
Iran has done nothing against India.
Iran has never launched a single
terrorist attack in into on India. Iran
has not sent a single terrorist into
India. Pakistan does that all the time.
And who funds and finances Pakistan? The
United States.
That's all I can say.
Fast snail says, "How does Navy
escorting containers at hormones help?"
It does not help. It does not help.
The Navy becomes a sitting ducks just
like the containers.
The Navy then has to defend the
container plus defend itself.
It It's not going to work out that way.
Defending sending navy naval warships to
escort containers is not going to open
the state of Armos. Doesn't work.
Birup Shark says if India were removed
from the from the swift from the swift
system how would the rupee hold up and
what investments besides gold would make
sense in India I think if India were
removed from the from the swift system
India's economy would would be
devastated India would not be able to do
any any uh economic transactions with
any other countries
and India would be devastated by that
yeah unless India participates in a
separate parallel system with the BRICS
nations. I think something that big is
being done right now. So the sooner that
comes up, the better it is for India. In
that case, the rupee will do will still
be impacted for sure, but will not do so
poorly. What investments besides gold
make sense in India? I don't know. I'm
not an an investing expert. Somebody can
give advice about that. So I can't say
Mishra, thank you very much. Ujul gi
uh DSCV Sri Lakshmi says I live in the
US. I came as a student and I'm working
here now. I agree with the analysis you
make about this country and how can I
make the best of here?
Okay. So you have you live in the US.
You came as a student and you're working
there now. What how can you make the
best of being in the US? Well the US
there are so many good things about the
US. The US is a land where you are
genuinely free and where there's
genuinely no limit to what you can
achieve.
So what can you do to make the best of
being there?
Take off. Whatever your dreams are,
pursue them. Work as hard as possible
and and go for it. In the US, you can
reach the fullest extent of your
potential. That's the thing about the
US. there are no artificial constraints
and restrictions and barriers like you
have in India.
Uh so without knowing you personally I
can't offer you any advice beyond that.
But I would say make the best of being
there. Right? Whatever dreams, hopes,
aspirations, ambitions you have, work on
them
with as much energy as possible and
do your best and and achieve whatever
you want to achieve. All right. All the
best. All the best, ma'am.
Ramaranga says, "Treat this as a
light-hearted question away from
geopolitics. Do for a second. Do you
wear dress watch, dive watch, or beater
watch on a daily basis? Or do you wear
Apple watch like the rest of the Ewoks?"
I don't have an Apple Watch. So, I don't
wear an Apple Watch.
I have a watch. My favorite watch is a
watch that I purchased 23 years ago from
Park City, Utah in the US. It's a watch
with a titanium strap.
Fossil watch. I'm not sure if it's a
dress watch, dive watch. I don't know
those ter terms. Beater watch. I I I
like that watch. That's my favorite
watch. Still works. And I have a couple
of other watches which yeah, dress watch
and so on. On a daily basis, I would
wear the that watch. My favorite watch.
I'm sure it can work as a dress watch.
It's it's pretty classy, elegant.
Yeah. And I don't wear Apple watch. I
don't have an Apple watch. I've never
bothered to buy one. So
Mishra says, "Appreciating you and how
to gain knowledge like you. Always be
curious or whatever whatever curiosity
you have, let it drive you and let it
make you learn new things and do read. I
got whatever knowledge I have from
reading reading."
Uh yeah.
An du says uh does geost strategy, game
theory, etc. suggest that superpowers
would always be the most aggressive and
hypocritical or can a superpower be a
world peacemaker? Game theory has
nothing to say about hypocrisy.
Okay, that's human nature. That game
theory says nothing about about
hypocrisy.
A strategy, geostrategy, well
geostrategy, it's based on various kinds
of models
including game theory. So that says
nothing about
Superpowers being hypocritic.
Hypocritical. Aggressive. Well,
aggression. Yeah. Game theory can tell
you about aggression. Aggression is a
strategy.
It's it's a valid strategy in depending
on what kind of game you're playing and
what the circumstances are. Uh can a
superpower be a world peacemaker? Well,
it can if it chooses to, but it is it's
it doesn't have the incentive to be a
world peacemaker. It's the incentive is
to Yeah. The incentive is to establish
world peace through strength by
suppressing everybody else. That's the
most logical way of manner for for a
superpower to proceed in. Right? So game
theory tells you what is the optimal
behavior for a player such as a powerful
nation given a c certain set of
circumstances and the other players who
are playing in playing the game and what
are their characteristics. Yeah, you can
set up all kinds of scenarios in game
theory based on this. So it doesn't say
anything about hypocrisy, but it does
say that superpower can be a world
peacemaker only by defeating everybody
else or subduing everybody else.
Na says in NCRT 11 chapter 8 advent of
Arian first page seems fake. I am so
sorry to hear this. I I've heard about
this problem that NCERT is still
peddling the Arian invasion or Arian
migration theory. Very unfortunate. Very
unfortunate. After all these years,
we're still doing this. Anyway, thank
you for letting us know, ma'am. Mlevin,
good to see you. Hand over the secret
panam and no one gets hurt. The secret
pranayam is walking pranayam. You can do
pranayam while walking.
That's the secret pranayam. You don't
have to sit with your eyes closed and do
whatever you're doing. You can do
pranayam with your eyes open while
walking. So you get the benefit of
exercise walking
plus the breath work the pranayam which
also is the first step towards
meditation the practice of meditation
you can do all of that while walking and
it's pretty difficult pretty difficult
at first you do it for 20 minutes you
feel like you've done surgery on
yourself that's how it feels the first
time you do it but yeah that is in my
opinion one of the most powerful forms
of pranaya
secret
uh trail trail says why is India bending
in front of front of the US to buy fuel
buy fuel from them also with respect to
Iran Israel war do you think Russia
strategically not interfering because
any other country because other
countries would rely on them for fuel
well it is in Russia's interest for this
war to go on for a long period of time
because that will help them sell a lot
of oil which is great for their economy
and it will finance the war against
Ukraine
So that from that perspective this war
the longer it lasts the better it is for
Russia as long as Iran is able to hold
its own. Okay. Now about India why is
India bending in front of the US to buy
fuel from them. India is trying its best
to maintain a decent relationship with
the US because we don't want to face
more pressure from the US. An example is
you know the US can impose all kinds of
economic, financial and strategic pain
on India.
So uh we are trying to the our best to
you know have a good relationship with
them. Obviously there will be lines we
will not cross.
If it feels like we are bending in front
of them, maybe we want that message to
go to the US that you know what we are
kind of being extra
uh differential to you especially
because Trump is that sort of guy who
wants that. But as long as India does
not compromise its vital interests, I
think it's okay as
as a ploy in game theory as as a as a as
a temporary strategy. It's okay as long
as it doesn't cross certain strategic
red lines for India. Gjapati Dave says
listening to Abijit Sar on ask versus
reading writing 30 minutes daily
suggested by Sar World War II like
confusing citizen situation for me.
Uh if you had the option of listening to
me for 30 minutes or writing for 30
minutes I would say go and write for 30
minutes. It will be better for you. But
if you have more time do listen to me as
well. I am not opposed to that at all.
But if you had a choice of only doing
this or that, listening to me for 30
minutes or writing for 30 minutes, I'll
say go right for 30 minutes. It'll be
better for you. World War II like confus
situation. Yeah, it's very confusing
because the things are happening
changing really fast. This situation is
called the fog of war by cloudsawitz.
Okay. The fog of war where everything is
confusing.
Fog of war concept.
It's taking longer than usual. Why is it
in Hindi? Danagri
fog of war
concept.
So what's this concept? the uncertainty,
the confusion and limited situational
awareness experienced by commanders and
soldiers during military operations
often caused by incomplete, inaccurate
or overwhelming information. So we as
non-combatants, we are facing, we are
also facing the same situation,
incomplete, inaccurate and overwhelming
quantity of information.
So that's the fog of war that we are
also experiencing despite being
non-combatants.
Hvei says reasons for this these events
not affecting the US dollar
because the global economy is still
underpinned by the US dollar or oil
transactions are still happening in the
US dollar. If you want if you want to
see dualization effects th those effects
will take a long time to happen. Okay,
that that happens over a long period of
time. A war you know within 7 days 10
days will not start affecting the US
dollar.
It will the US dollar will will it its
status will change
depending
on whether nations stop purchasing oil
in US dollars or not and a whole set of
other um other data points as well. So
these things happen slowly. You know
there's there's a typically a lag
between cause and effect in some sports
sports
the there is an you will see the effect
immediately but in some sports you will
see a lag between cause and effect. For
example, yeah most sports you will see
it immediately that you change your
strategy and you will see the changes
immediately. But for example, if you
want to become a bodybuilder and you
start eating protein like a high protein
diet and start going to gym regularly 5
days a week or whatever following a
proper diet plan, it'll take you 3 to 6
months to see the effects. So similarly
some things there's a lag between
something happening and the effect
becoming visible.
Bishall says did regional kingdoms
weaken pan Indian unity? No.
Civilizational unity not weakened.
Political unity of course weakened when
you have kingdoms instead of a single
empire. Political unity is obviously
impacted by that. Yeah. Mudit says are
new Epstein images showing Hawking in
Bill's lap. True. I I haven't seen that.
Bill Hawking in Bill's lap. I don't even
want to see that. Thank you. I don't
know. I don't know.
Hershel says, "Is the entropy of the
universe reducing or increasing? What
does it mean for our planet and how does
it affect the nature of time? Is time
and entropy correlated in some way?
Entropy is a measure of disorder. Let me
give you a very simple example. Look at
my my background. H is is books here.
You can see books. It's real books. It's
not a it's not a wallpaper. It's real
books. So, you can see it's all very
orderly. I've got some dinosaurs up here
and some all the stuff. But it's all
kept orderly. So, when you have this
kind of order,
it's called that. It means that this
this um room that I am in the system
that I'm in is a low entropy system,
highly ordered system. But consider a
scenario where I have pens and cables on
the floor and books thrown around and
clothes lying on the floor. It's
complete mess. It's a complete disorder,
right? That's a high entropy system. So
the question is is the entropy of the
universe reducing or increasing? Which
means is the amount of order or disorder
of the universe increasing or
decreasing? And uh thermodynamics tells
us that entropy either stays the same or
increases. The universe is a system. So
the entropy of the universe is
increasing over time. What does it mean
for a planet and how does it affect the
nature of time? It means that for our
planet eventually the planet will go to
dust. Eventually it'll be transformed
into dust.
When the sun becomes a red super giant
red giant
the outer layers of the sun will engulf
the the earth. they'll go beyond Earth's
orbit. So, Earth will be burnt to a
crisp. Eventually, the sun will die. It
will spend its last billions of years as
as a white dwarf
and earth eventually will crumble into
nothingness.
Uh so, that's what it means for for a
planet. Because entropy increases, how
does it affect the nature of time? Is
time and entropy correlated in some way?
Possibly the the error of time, the
unidirectional error of time perhaps has
something to do with entropy. Perhaps
perhaps also perhaps quantum
entanglement and so on. That is a long
discussion but possibly that's that's a
theory but it's not proven. It's a good
it's an interesting theory though. Sur
says want to see Milky Way with the
naked eyes naked eye. Suggestions well
today if you live in any city in India
you can't see the Milky Way with him
with your naked eye. My suggestion is
well go to a place where there is no
light pollution. Hard to find places.
One place I have found is the tours of
Lake Pangong
in Lada. If you go to Ladak, you will
see the Milky Way in its full glory. So
go to a place like that. You don't have
to go to Ladak. It's a very difficult
place for most people. Most people are
can't take the altitude. But go to a
place like that where there's no light
pollution. Then you will see the Milky
Way. I still remember the first time I
saw the Milky Way and realized what it
was. I must have been two or three years
old and I saw I had very sharp eyesight
as a kid at the time and I see this
incredible quantity of stars and so many
stars it looks like a cloud but I can
discern there are individual stars there
but from afar it looks like a cloud that
for the first time
drove home the realization for me how
vast our own galaxy is the number of
stars and each star is like our sun that
staggered me I was a kid like little kid
toddler. So yeah, go to a place like
that then you can watch it then then you
can see it in its full glory.
User says anything on Pakistan Israel
nexus in the secret cooperation.
Um
I don't have any new
uh understanding of it. See the what I
have to say is very simple and
straightforward. It's logical. Israel is
America's number one asset uh number one
ally.
America gives unconditional support to
Israel, right? And Pakistan is one of
America's principal vasal states. So if
America and Israel are on the same side,
they are both allies. And Pakistan is
America's vasal state, then what's the
relationship between Pakistan and Isra
and Israel? That's the big question. And
Pakistan seems to be on the side of the
of the US and Israel in this war.
So clearly there is more to this
relationship than meets the eye. But
what's the secret cooperation? I have no
idea. I don't have secret information.
Goullibar says, "I know you from TRS.
Any plans to on going to TRS again?" I
go there from time to time.
Uh so I'm glad that you know me from TRS
and I'll keep going to TRS. Yeah, that
that's going to keep going on. I'm sure
sooner or later. Once again,
Sugpa says, "My girlfriend is pursuing
as data analyst emerging AI threat and
future opportunities in IT sector
particularly the this role. Your
thoughts on this? Thank you so much."
Okay.
Okay. She is she wants to be a data
analyst. emerging AI threat and future
opportunities in IT sector particularly
this role data analyst role or you can
do a tremendous amount of data analysis
using AI
let's say you have a data set let's say
it's a CSV file let's say it's tab
whatever format the file is let's say
you've got a tremendous amount of data
for a particular company that business
let's say legacy data 20 years of data
you can take all of this data and dump
it into an industrial scale AI Okay,
industrial
enterprise scale AI and the AI is going
to go through everything. It's going to
give you tremendous insights about the
data. Let's say you are a single uh
oneperson business. Let's say you're an
entrepreneur and you've got Excel sheets
full of data,
okay? sales and
sales whatever invoices
um all of that you know expenditure
and so on so forth AI can take that AI
can go through your through your email
it can synthesize all the information
and give you insights you would not
believe were possible
data analysis is going to be eaten alive
by AI that is how I see things going
unfortunately. Just telling you.
All right. All the best to you and your
girlfriend. All the best. Keep this in
mind.
Okay. V Ruth.
Okay. Prrenav, if the US has advanced
weapons from Area 51, then why not
using? Well, that's a good question. I
don't know if they have advanced weapons
from Area 51, but if they have it, why
are they not using that stuff? That's a
good question, and I I don't have an
answer to that. I have not claimed that
they have advanced weapons from Area 51.
But the UFO things that we see, they
seem to be advanced technology that they
are developing.
But why haven't they used in this war?
Maybe this is not a big enough war for
that. Maybe those weapons are to be kept
for the final most important war. Maybe
don't don't show that right now.
Vipul Pavar says if spaceime is
emergent, what's the fundamental
structure from which geometry arises? We
nobody has the answer. We don't know if
spacetime is emergent or not.
emergence spacetime. We're talking about
LQG
loop quantum gravity.
In that you have a fundamental unit of
space time and a fundamental volume of
spaceime right 10 to - 99 or so meters
cubic meters roughly um
what's the fundamental structure from
which geometry arises arises quantum
form I suppose quantum form
so we only have speculative theories
right now
and theories like loop quantum gravity
etc
And they don't make see for a theory to
be taken seriously it has to make
testable predictions and these theories
don't make testable predictions as of
now. So these are very speculative
theories nice mathematical theories and
I would say pretty grounded theories but
still don't make any testable
predictions that I am aware of. So
we don't have answers to these
questions.
We we talking about scales you can't
imagine. Imagine a volume of 10 raised
to - 99 cubic m. I mean can you even
imagine that it's way way way way
smaller than the plank plank scale.
So this is
it's it's mostly speculation right now.
We don't have any concrete answers.
Pranit Kumar says since Indian Hindu
diaspora is increasing in the US
there are many Hindu billionaires in the
US chance of Hindu lobby in the future
like a Jewish lobby in the US? No.
Hindus never unite.
Have you ever seen anybody hering cats
together? No. Right. Uh yeah, there's no
chance of a Hindu lobby in the US. I
don't see that happening.
HF says, "How will this war affect China
and Pakistan?" It depends on how it
goes. Uh if the war goes longer, the
Americans use Chinese territory for
attacking Iran, then China then, sorry,
Pakistani territory for attacking Iran,
then Pakistan does get dragged into the
war. And that's a big problem for
Pakistan. China, well, if the American
supplies of arms, ammunition, etc. get
depleted and the Americans have to
cannibalize their positions in East Asia
then that benefits China. Okay.
Okay. It's been more than 4 hours. I got
to end this soon. Sanju says, "According
to you, whom do you think to be the best
king India ever had in terms of
security, growth, and prosperity?" Also,
I bow down before your knowledge. Please
don't do that. But anyway, thank you
very much. The best king India ever had
in terms of security, growth, and
prosperity. If you're asking about the
last 2,000 years,
um I can give several candidates. One is
Kanishka the great. Uh another is
um
another is uh Samudra Gupta.
One more I would say Rajendra Chola
and of course Chhatraat Shivaji Maharaj
the great uh even though he did not see
the full extent of his the empire he
founded but yeah who was the greatest if
you were to ask me if you if I had to
take one name I would say Kaneshka the
great I would say Ganeshuka no offense
to anybody else but I would say Kaneshka
in the past 20 maybe in the first
millennium AD
Gulibar says US Greenland issue. Is it
closed or dormant? It's dormant.
Dormant.
Global says, "Do you prefer Linux or
Windows?" I have never used Linux.
Never used it. I once studied Linux for
a while. Command line and vi editor and
stuff. Very very long ago, but I use
Windows and iOS.
So I don't have much experience, very
almost negligible experience with Linux.
Jam says, "Why do banks like rosils fund
global wars?" Well, I don't know if they
do, and if they do, I don't know why.
Maybe it's about world domination.
GG's says, "We've been talking about
Indian economy in education system, but
how can we actually bring rapid changes,
rapid, real rapid changes, not tiny
increments? We can't. Only the
government can. The common person can't
do a thing about this. People like me
can only talk about it and recommend
what needs to be done. But the only
people who have the power to make
changes are the government. The people
in the government. They can bring about
changes by passing laws by by drafting,
formulating policies and implementing
them. Easy stuff. They can do it. They
can do make changes through the stroke
of a pen and have these changes become
real world changes. They can do it, but
they choose not to do it.
Sanu says have you gone through the
works of Dr.
Nilant Oak on Raman Mahabarat proofs. Do
you agree with him? He talks about
Norway to win it. I have not gone
through it. I I have not studied his
work so I can't say I don't have an
opinion about it.
Govin says can Iran attack US mainland
in any way like launch a missile just to
scare them? Look when you launch a
missile it's no longer scaring them. is
actually taking actually taking action
right which can actually damage
something in the US maybe do some damage
possibly serious damage can the can Iran
do that I don't know if Iran has the
capability the capacity to attack the
American mainland through missiles for
example I don't think Iranian missiles
have that sort of range ICBM
intercontinental range I don't think so
I not that I know of so as far as I know
it's not the case they don't have the
capac capability other more innovative
ways well I'll not go there
adita says why no country came forward
to support India in operation sindur
especially after giving free covid
vaccines against Pakistan who are our
real partners who are our real partners
no friend not friends we have no real
partners India stands alone okay
India stands alone why did no country
come forward to support India in
operation hindor after we gave free
covid vaccines to everybody
Because that's not how the world works.
You give something for free, people will
take it for granted.
If you give something in a way that
there is reciprocity, a reciprocity
agreement which is signed legally and
you have the power to enforce it,
then they will agree to then they will
act as per the agreement. So giving
things for free is like throwing things
out of a moving car.
There's no point doing it in my opinion.
Krishant Bordo says bit off topic but
please react to Durand 2 trailer but be
careful about copyright strike. I am not
playing a trailer here. I've not watched
it. I'm not aware of it. Has it come out
the trailer and I if I play it here I
could get a copyright strike. So I will
watch it offline and um I'll see at
least I thank you for letting me know
it's this trailer is out. I do look
forward to watching the movie the second
part. Yeah. Gibbar says you said the
earth will eventually be dust. What's
the point of geopolitics cha blah blah
at the end it doesn't matter. Me
the earth will be dust in 5 billion 6
billion years.
It doesn't matter what happens at that
time to us. What matters is what we do
in our lifetime.
Do we make our life a meaningful life?
every life is going to end. Then why do
we even live?
That's not the right approach to life.
As long as we are here, can we make this
a meaningful life? That's the only thing
that matters.
The earth will eventually dust be dust.
That doesn't matter. What we do with the
time we have on this in this universe is
what matters. So I think it all matters.
It all matters. Maybe it's just a game
then. Let's play the game and enjoy it.
That's how I see it.
Okay. DSCV Shri Lakmi says, "Thanks for
the advice. I really enjoy live stream.
I'm 24 years old and working in
environmental consulting. You are very
welcome, ma'am. You're very young. You
have a long way forward ahead of you and
I think you can achieve anything you
want to achieve as long as you put in
the right effort, the right energy and
you work smart, not just hard." All
right. So thank you so much for your
very kind words. Thank you for being a
viewer and all the best. I wish you
success.
Putin says, "Can Yugi GI do a precision
like rebellion against Modi? I don't
ever imagine that happening."
Miguel Maniac is why experts all around
the world are criticizing Modi. It's
maybe a concerted campaign to create a
certain kind of narrative about India.
Yeah.
Okay. That brings me to to the end of
this live stream. Finally, after 4 hours
19 minutes, let's wrap it up. Thank you
so much everybody for your questions.
Thank you for your viewership. I really
appreciate it. Uh, keep asking
questions, keep raising your standards,
and I shall see you on Saturday. There's
a bit of a break because I'm traveling,
but I shall see you next on Saturday. I
look forward to seeing you there. Until
then, take care. See you soon.